discussion
today on marriage and the sanctions and
the sanctuary and it is our last part
which
man makes me kind of sad but not really
because we will come back and revisit it
it's such a big thing I mean this time
we're doing it through the sanctuary
next time who knows which way we'll do
it but we will we will come back to it
but uh we are we we've learned so much
um throughout this series
um how many how many of you put a put a
two in the chat if you were super
blessed by the daily Elms two-part
presentation I know I was uh we had Dr
White on and then we did a few by
ourselves as well but um this is going
to be the grand finale I think you're
really going to be blessed by this but
it has been uh the whole series has been
a huge blessing and again you know we
talk about uh marriage and especially
you know some people may think well like
you know hey they shouldn't think this
but some may think like Hey we're
Christians so we don't have any issues
with marriage that there could nothing
could be further from the truth uh
marriage is challenging and whether
you're a Christian or not a Christian I
mean as a Christian we have we should
know the tools and what to do when our
marriage gets into a rocky place but
even then
um we don't always have we're not we
don't we don't access those tools so
easily so
um it's like what we've discussed before
that marriage ends up in divorce the
statistic are 50 50 percent and then in
the church is 51 so it's just basically
about the same and so hopefully through
this series
um uh that this will help better your
marriage and if your marriage is you
know in a crisis hopefully it will be
you know just you know that thing that
you needed to just help to get it into a
better place and then maybe you can seek
mental health professionals like with
counseling marriage counseling that can
also be extremely beneficial and I say
that because I'm a marriage and family
therapist and I know what counseling and
therapist therapy can do uh for a
marriage so if it's in a crisis
definitely encourage you to to seek
someone
that that can help you in that and if
your marriage is good then this series
will just make it better so
that that's our that's our goal but we
always have announcements and we didn't
get to to any of that yeah so yeah so
just want to encourage everyone
especially uh if you have not yet if you
only watched on Sabbath and you have not
participated in all the things that
living manage Church offers during the
week
I feel kind of sorry for you because we
have great programming and information
that happens all throughout the week we
have Monday mental health Mondays uh Dr
Ricardo white and I co-host that
together and we're actually going uh
through relationships and we've been
using
um the the gottman uh studies and series
and this will be this next one will be
our third uh time and that's been
um that's been a blessing to be able to
share that we also have true Health
Tuesdays with Dr schweltz and Dr Kenisha
Reynolds that is just man put in the
chat put a three in the chat if you have
been so blessed by true Health Tuesdays
like the information that you've learned
but no don't put a three if you've been
blessed put a three if you've actually
applied some of the information that
you've been learning uh because I know
that a lot of yes there's some threes
it's been so good it's like learning
this health education stuff that we all
need to know to to be as healthy as we
can possibly be and then we have power
Wednesdays
um that is led by our prayer team and
that and uh brother Terry is the leader
of that but he has a prayer team uh that
is phenomenal and so
um they all help uh lead out in that
prayer service I heard a powerful
testimony this week and I can't remember
the sister's name I man if you guys were
there listening put it in the chat
because it was very powerful
um and I think she said her and her
husband pray every day at 12 o'clock no
matter like where they are I think
that's exactly I think that's what she
said but her testimony is very very
powerful and so so you get prayer and
they've been
um
showcasing testimonies people are giving
their live testimonies which have been
um a blessing so definitely check out uh
Power Wednesdays um it is truly truly a
blessing uh with our prayer team and
then Dr Panda on Thursdays
um and also put a four I'm gonna put a
four in the chat if you have I've been
blessed by what Dr pan did is sharing
and you feel like you could actually
somebody you could actually you feel
like you could share with someone who is
an atheist or agnostic and you feel like
you can uh By Hearing uh what Dr Panda
has been sharing you feel comfortable
enough uh sharing with someone who maybe
not his whole study I'm not saying that
but just some of the things that he has
um has provided and shared um just put a
four okay we've got a four okay that you
feel comfortable enough to be able to do
that and that is the point of living man
at church and we are still okay we got a
lot of fours okay Michelle she feels
very very comfortable
is god
um and we are still in the process of
working on our outreach program so our
outreach program is going to be launched
here very soon so pray for that under
the leadership of Janet Abby so
definitely pray for that and it's under
the leadership of Jana Abby but this is
something where we all get involved and
we are going to go out and be the hands
and feet of Jesus into our local
communities which is represented all
around the world as we were just
mentioning how where people are watching
from so that is what living manage
church is currently doing and we always
solicit your prayers amen always
yeah so I think with with that we are
gonna go ahead and jump into our study
and now that we're taking your questions
as well yeah so we're gonna have a word
of prayer and uh and then we're going to
do a little recap yes and then continue
on where we left off so
um let's go ahead and pray
Heavenly Father we thank you Lord for uh
all that you've been doing for us Lord
we thank you for
um this Sanctuary truth Lord and we just
pray Lord that as we uh complete this
study today Lord on on marriage and the
sanctuary solution that you would just
bless those that are watching and uh may
this uh may this study Lord may this
series uh save marriages is our prayer
in Jesus name strengthen marriages as
well is our prayer in Jesus name amen
amen amen amen all right
so uh we're gonna go to the screen and
uh we're gonna do a little recap here so
um we have seen that the sanctuary
service the Bible says thy way oh God is
in the sanctuary and uh we have been
discussing over the over the last
several weeks in this series that the
sanctuary is the tool that God himself
used
to fix his broken marriage right and the
marriage was not broken because of God
the marriage was broken because of
humanity
right because of us so
the sanctuary service
if God uses it to heal his marriage how
much more ought we to look to the
sanctuary for the solution right for our
marriages whether that is to strengthen
them to revive them whatever is
necessary
um we saw that inside the sanctuary
itself uh there were six articles of
furniture and these articles of
furniture we saw represented various
principles
within the sanctuary so the altar of
sacrifice representing the principle of
self-sacrificing love in a in a
relationship
um the labor representing the principle
of forgiveness uh in a relationship the
table of showbread representing the
principle of
communication in a relationship the
altar of incense representing the
principle of uh intimacy emotional
Intimacy in a relationship the
candlestick fire passion representing
that physical passion in a relationship
and now we're
concluding with uh the final part of the
sanctuary which is the most holy place
right we we said that we want to move
from an outer Court relationship to a
holy Place relationship ultimately to a
Most Holy Place relationship right
um so let's notice what's in the most
holy place I'm going to read this and
this is going to kind of set us up for
what we're going to be talking about for
the rest of the time so
in Hebrews 9 verse 1 the Bible says then
verily the first Covenant had also
ordinances of divine services and a
worldly sanctuary
for there was a tabernacle made the
first were in was the Candlestick and
the table and the showbread which is
called the sanctuary and after the
second Veil The Tabernacle which is
called the holiest of all
it says in verse 4.
which had the golden sensor
and the Ark of the Covenant overlaid
roundabout with gold wherein was the
golden pot that had manna
and Aaron's Rod that buddy
and the tables of the Covenant and over
it the cherubim of Glory shadowing The
Mercy Seat of which we cannot now
particularly speak
so let me let me just come back for a
moment
um
and what we're seeing here is that the
sanctuary Works in a process right so we
started at the altar sacrifice we moved
to the labor and we spent a week roughly
a week to two weeks on each article of
furniture showing their importance in
the relationship right showing why it's
important to have self-sacrificing love
why it's important to have mercy and
forgiveness why communication and all
these different things are important
healthy communication healthy
communication we saw that in order for
the Candlestick and the table of
showbread and the altar of incense which
is all in a holy place to be working
efficiently we first have to master the
outer court right right be willing to
lay down our own our own you know
self-sacrifice for your spouse altered
sacrifice being willing to forgive
that's the labor right the washing away
of sin right
um and so that's how we move into a holy
Place relationship you cannot move into
a holy Place relationship if the altar
of sacrifice and the labor aren't
working right and see we've been going
over practical principles how do we
learn how to lay self down how do we
learn how to uh forgive and and wash
away the past right wash away your
mistakes how do we
um learn to do those things so that we
can have pure communication we can have
true emotional intimacy and we can have
true physical intimacy right okay
so that's all been recap
when we get into the most holy place
there's something I want you to see here
we just saw
let me go back to the screen here
um that there are
five listen carefully to this now
there's The Mercy Seat
there's the golden pot of Mana
there's the golden sensor there's
Aaron's Rod that budded
and there's the Ark of the Covenant The
Ten Commandments inside the Ark of the
Covenant so
um you'll notice here that there are
five
five different items
that are located in the most holy place
why is this significant and again this
is setting the foundation for what we're
going to talk about in this presentation
notice
note in fact let me just do this let me
say it this way
these five items
that are found in the most holy place
are in essence
pieces
of
the five articles of furniture
found in the outer court and the holy
place so they're connected it's almost
as if the most holy place is a
combination
of everything
in the Holy place and the outer Court it
brings it all together
put a one in the chat if you understand
what I'm saying and while you're
struggling with that one if you are I'm
just gonna go to the next slide and show
you so watch this
the the altar of sacrifice
right
represents self-sacrificing love but
this is the very definition of the law
that is found in the Ark of the Covenant
right right the Bible says greater love
has no man than this and a man lay down
his life for his friends the Bible says
that love is the fulfilling of the law
so when you look at the Ark of the
Covenant you're actually seeing the very
same principle that is found at the
altar of sacrifice right
okay so let's go to the labor remember
the labor is about forgiveness the labor
is about washing away the past well
guess what that parallels the mercy
seats in the most holy place
because The Mercy Seat is all about
extending Mercy it's about extending
forgiveness so in The Mercy Seat you
actually have a piece of the labor
well what about the table of Soul bread
ah the table of showbread
parallels the golden part of manna yes
so in the in the in the with the manner
in the most holy place it's almost like
it's a piece of that table of showbread
that is being brought into the most holy
Place well what about the golden sensor
so the golden sensor is not the altar of
incense the golden sensor was the the
the the the item that the priests used
to carry incense right into the most
holy place and Paul puts the golden
sensor in the most holy place that
golden sensor is is connected with the
altar of incense which is the principle
of prayer the principle that we talked
about emotional intimacy all right what
about Aaron's Rod that buddy remember
Aaron's Rod is a stick
and that parallels the seven Branch
candle stick remember if you read about
the Candlestick you'll see that the
Candlestick butted and blossomed and
bloomed in other words they were to
create Buds and Blossoms and blooms in
the Candlestick itself so the
Candlestick and the Aaron's rod in the
most holy place is almost like a piece
of the Candlestick being brought in that
in essence is telling us that the most
holy place
is really a combination of all the
principles of the previous right of the
previous articles of the sanctuary okay
so
put a one in the chat if you all got
that just now because basically what
we're just seeing is listen
in order for
for that most holy place
relationship to happen
you must
exercise all those articles of furniture
right simultaneously
right it's not good enough to just
practice one right and then be like all
right we're good and not practice the
other
I like to say that the
um
like the most holy Place marriage
experience is not one and done
um and I I was explaining to Ivory
yesterday I was like I look at it as
like it's maintenance so you you know
you you're practicing all of these
different
um pieces of furniture and that's gotten
your marriage to be in a place where you
could say okay it's a Most Holy Place uh
we're at a Most Holy Place experience uh
but all of these different the the five
articles of furniture that are in the
most holy place are representing how to
maintain uh that marriage that you have
achieved that's it that's in a healthy
space because you've practiced all the
other articles of furniture yeah
um you
each article if you if you consider each
article by themselves uh it's almost
like God is saying listen
the most holy place is the ultimate
definition of love it's the ultimate
definition of atonement or at one minute
so with that in mind
we have to realize that
um
actually
each article is teaching us a little
piece of how to get into that most holy
Place relationship right so
like it's possible to really like like
to communicate with your spouse table of
showbread hey I like communicating with
with my spouse but there's still no
emotional intimacy right you're
communicating but you're not
communicating on a deep level
yeah okay okay or or
um
you might forgive labor right Mercy Seat
I forgive you but I'm just not talking
to you anymore which really isn't
forgiveness right right right
uh or you might just be interested in
the candidate right I just want to be
physically intimate with you but I don't
you know as far as this community I'm
not going to have an emotional yeah I'm
not going to have a
culture of incense emotional connection
with you but I'll
do the Candlestick so
each one of those in essence you can't
really do one of these right without if
you're just doing one of these and
you're not really doing the Candlestick
because it's yes physical without any
emotional connection and passion so the
the brightness or the fire is not there
yeah you if you're
if you're lagging on any one of these
articles of furniture the whole thing is
lagging
right the whole thing is lagging so
we're learning how to do this
daily right
right you learn how to it's a process
that you go through all right we started
think of it like this right instead of
instead of
hey last week we were in the outer Court
this week we're in the Holy place right
and hopefully we'll get to the most holy
Place think of it as every day you can
have that experience of
every day start in the outer Court
right you're starting in the outer Court
you got to make sure you know what self
is self is dead
you got to make sure that labor is
working you don't know what's going to
come up throughout the day make sure
that Labor's working all these these
articles of furniture
you can practice them daily so that on
the large scale right the most holy
Place scale that is something that
you're living in most holy place because
every day so
there's this uh thing in the in the Old
Testament called the Tami
which means the daily and basically what
it meant was that these articles of
furniture the priests
basically functioned at these articles
of furniture daily yes right the
Candlestick was to be uh trimmed daily
the altar of incense was to be trimmed
daily like they would attend to these
things
daily
so
that's the principle for us right we
can't be like all right cool I'm out of
I'm out of the uh out of the uh outer
court now now I'm living in the no it's
a daily process it's something that we
have to go through on a daily basis and
that is what allows us I think to to
move our relationship on a on a
macro scale to be continually in the
most holy place
yes
um and I was going to say you know one
of the the things that is in the uh Most
Holy place was the uh golden pot of
manna and looking at that you know I
immediately was connecting it to the
table of showbread which represents
um in this marriage study communication
uh the way we communicate with our
spouse but I was it was interesting that
was in a a golden pot of Madness so it
represents healthy
um communication and and so and there is
there is a technique to have healthy
communication
um in a marriage you know when not you
don't always have something sometimes
things come up in your marriage and they
and you feel compelled that you need to
say something and it is in that time
that you still want to have healthy uh
communication and it's a two-way uh
thing that that happens you feel like
you need to say something to your spouse
that is not an easy thing to say or you
might have a little fear that it
normally would cause an argument or it
just it just never really goes well
um and so communication with your spouse
or in a marriage is a two-way street so
you're communicating something and the
spouse is to be listening with empathy
and understanding so we should always be
providing our spouse a safe space to be
able to communicate what they feel they
need to communicate and as the
communicator the one that's going to
communicate you should always be
extremely Mindful and
uh respectful of the space that your
spouse is in because they're about to
hear something that you're about to
communicate so you want to can be do you
want to communicate that
um in a way
um that is is not
um that's not going to shut them down
that's not going to make them want to
put up their walls and be defensive uh
right away but you're coming at them
like we we shared this in mental health
Mondays uh with the ease with assault
and we shared it here too with a soft
startup so you're you're coming at them
um with you know with kindness and um
with love even though what you're going
to share might be a little difficult
because this is a marriage right it's
not always we don't always have to we
don't always have things that are
flowery to communicate sometimes we have
some things that are are difficult and
so your work you're presenting in that
type of way and the spouse that is
listening when you're you know going
back to the golden pot of Mana having
this golden communication you're
providing a safe space for your spouse
to be able to communicate whatever
they're needing to communicate and we
want to give an example of what that
looks like because I'm the queen of
being practical because I know you guys
want real practical things and of course
you're learning a lot here but you want
to be able to
see what that really looks like so are
we going to give an example I don't know
okay we're going to give an example this
is something
um that you know this is a principle
that I use when I'm working with
couples who say you know we have we have
trouble communicating which every couple
comes in and says they want to work on
communication and and really since we've
been doing the studies it really the
communication or is it the first article
of furniture it's the first art yeah
it's the first article of furniture it's
you know having that self-sacrificing
love and
and that so but everybody comes in and
says they want to work on communication
so to have healthy communication to get
but now you are you know in your you
have this golden pot of Mana so you have
healthy communication but the way you're
able to do maintenance and and maintain
that healthy communication is again
providing that healthy safe uh space so
you're communicating with
um empathy and understanding and so what
I tell
are direct my clients to do is we're
gonna we're gonna actually do it here
returning towards each other so you like
you know grab hands look into each
other's eyes
um I'm still gonna look at you for a
second because I'm gonna give further
instruction so uh one person speaks at a
time
um obviously the one who's bringing the
issue
um is gonna is gonna start and um we can
let go now because I have to say some
more hold on we'll come back to that so
um the first person is that wants to
share is gonna start and the other
person you're listening with empathy and
understanding so you know like when you
go I like to use this as an analogy when
you go to somebody's house because you
guys know I'm big about shoes not being
in the house wearing shoes in the house
so
um when you go to somebody's house and
you realize you're a guest and you
realize that they don't want you to wear
your shoes in their house because you're
a guest you're very respectful and you
say okay I'm gonna take my shoes off and
so using that principle when you're
listening to your spouse like you are
entering into their heart you are a
guest into their heart and mind and so
you want to be very respect respectful
and you're listening from a stance of
um of empathy so you're like really uh
want to hear what they have to say and
you really care about what they are
about to say so much so that at the end
of your spouse saying whatever they have
to say
you almost become
that person because you're listening so
intently right and so when they're done
sharing like if I if I share something
with Ivor and he's listening with
empathy and understanding at the end for
me to know that he really understood it
he has to repeat what I said and it
doesn't have to be word for word but
just in general so he'll say
I'm a tante and I feel and then he'll
say what I said and then I'll know that
he really heard and understood me and if
he you know got something a little wrong
I can respectfully correct him and say
oh what I was actually saying was x y
and z so if that makes sense so are we
going to do a little example okay this
is what I tell my clients too you have
to choose something they have to they do
it in front of me and they and I say
pretend I'm not here so we're going to
pretend like you guys are not here and
um you have to do something that you
know is real that actually you're going
through so so here's a little example
um
Okay so
you know I get easily
stressed when things are not
in order the way they should should be
and so I
um I don't want to be that person that
gets stressed out so but what I need
from you is to
um just try to prepare things that you
know that are happening in the future
and like
organize it in a way that can help me to
not
be get so stressed out so easily because
I don't want to be that stressed out
person
Okay so amatante
and I feel that you could really help me
not be stressed if you were uh to plan
those things that happen in the future
uh better in advance
right
right okay
okay so that was an example I hope that
was an example and that was real too
so um
uh yes and that's how you can keep
the maintenance part that that golden uh
the Mana and the golden pot that's how
you can keep your communication
healthy in your marriage when you need
to discuss things especially things that
are difficult
um then
that is that is one of the ways that I
that I that I have seen be life-changing
in marriages that have a hard time
communicating yeah
so I think you have you know you have
the golden pot we looked at how each one
of these articles
is really trying to teach us how to
um how to bring it together yes right I
think I forgot go ahead is your body
language because we speak with our body
language too so even your body language
has to be towards the heart of you or it
has to speak as as what you're really
feeling trying to get into the heart of
your spouse so even that place when
you're doing that if you're actually
going to practice doing that exercise or
that actual thing even your body
language has to
to be the way that your heart and mind
should be empathy and understanding it
should be saying that yeah
so yeah again I was you know kind of
pointing out that the
uh the purpose of or the experience of
the most holy place is learning how to
bring all of this together to function
at the same time right uh and that takes
that takes practice uh each one of these
articles we've gone over in detail this
is you know this is what it means to be
uh emotionally intimate how you can get
emotional intimacy how you can become we
talk about physical intimacy last two
weeks and we're like listen if you're
not communicating at the table show grid
if you don't have emotional intimacy
you're not gonna have real physical
intimacy right at the Candlestick uh if
you're holding on to resentment if
you're not uh laying yourself down kind
of self-sacrificing you're not going to
experience that kind of intimacy so
the the most holy place again it brings
it brings all of it together
and it's basically showing us
in order to have that kind of marriage
that is you know
um uh uh Pastor DeLeon called it the
Shekinah experience right right the
Shekinah experience where you are seeing
the glory of God in your marriage right
this is this is what is required and
even thinking about that that uh Aaron's
Rod right the purpose of Aaron's rod
when when they put up Aaron's Rob in the
Ark of the Covenant it was because
the rod or Rod is a dead stick right
right but God was able to bring it to
life you shouldn't be able to budge so
man my marriage is dead my you know I
just feel like the there's nothing that
can be I can't restore this
God says listen I can bring it back to
life yes right through my power I can
bring it back to life so and keep it
yeah and sustain it yep
so this is this is what
when we're looking at these articles of
furniture they're giving us so many
different lessons encouragement right as
to what the possibilities are
in your marriage what can happen if you
allow God to work if you allow God's way
which is in the sanctuary to actually be
the way you're going to try to heal or
strengthen your marriage right so again
every article of furniture is giving us
a principle and this is uh
I mean we haven't exhausted this
there are things that P that as you're
studying you're looking at the all right
so the sanctuary is the way well let me
look at some more there's so much there
right that we haven't even covered but
let's
you want to talk about the Commandments
yeah yeah so let's talk about the
Commandments and you know what what
we're what we're doing here is we're
looking particularly at the Ark of the
Covenant specifically The Ten
Commandments and we're asking how can we
translate some of these Commandments
into our marriages right and you know
one of them when you think of the first
two Commandments thou shall have no
other gods before me thou shall not have
any Grieving images it's God is saying
do not put anything before me right okay
so on a human level
when we're relating this to marriage if
you're looking at these Ten Commandments
as it relates to marriage in essence
we shouldn't be putting anything before
our marriage right outside of God and
God is not you know God is the god of
marriage but
we shouldn't be allowing anything to
come before right our relationship with
one another right
that's gonna because that will damage
the relationship right obviously
not another person not not object not an
object not money not
work I mean of course we have to work
but there should be a balance of you
know you're putting time into your your
spouse as well
um not not a hobby like you should
definitely do have a hobby and you have
something you know your guys's
individual things that you like and do
but nothing should be be over or put
that before your spouse
so
think of this as
you know breaking the marriage
Commandments right breaking the marriage
Commandments if I'm putting things
before my spouse they're gonna get to
sense that they're gonna they're gonna
begin to feel that right and the
Commandments taught you know deals with
our marriage our relationship with God
right
um yes Jody including children yeah
including children
and I'm I'm sorry I'm just I'm just
because it's all that comment and I just
bought I want to touch that and that's
why it's so important I don't know I
mentioned it a few weeks ago about like
and we I think we did it with the daily
guns too but the date night
um just
making sure that you have you and your
spouse have that individual time or two
hours a week where you have that
individual time that's just for you it's
not your kids like your kids cannot go
on your date tonight they cannot be a
part of it at all it is just for you and
your spouse so yes children absolutely
not yeah but remember now you know
children need to be raised they need to
be taken care of yes just yeah yeah just
for those two hours or just for that
time each week that you guys reconnect
yeah that's important right you you
don't
we're not saying don't care about your
kids we're simply saying that your
relationship with your kids is different
from your relationship with your spouse
those are two different relationships so
and you're actually caring about your
kids when you make sure that you
reconnect every week with your spouse
because you're gonna have a better
marriage which is going to make them
happy because if you just dealing with
them and you don't have a healthy
marriage or you're putting time into
your marriage it's going to make your
children unhappy yeah because Mommy and
Daddy are not happy yeah and uh you know
think about the fourth Commandment right
God says I want you to take time out
every week to spend with me well let's
translate that into the marriage right
it's learning how to take time out and
what you were just talking about every
week learning how to take time out and
spend that time with that like have a
dedicated
with your spouse right I was like I
didn't get that wrong yeah okay I got it
right just take a dedicated take some
dedicated time sabotees most of the rest
yeah whether that's daily weekly
whatever you guys decide yeah you know
every week we're gonna do this every
month we're going away because God does
that with his spouse he wants his spouse
to do that absolutely absolutely so you
want to make sure that you're you're
setting aside that time that special
time right God says I want you to do and
uh you know he doesn't want you to do
anything I want you to be focused on us
right right and that's what we want in
the Mad relationship time that we can
focus on our you know spouses can focus
on each other I said this before but I
have a colleague that I worked with back
in California who wrote a book called
over date
and again we do we over we overeat we
overwork we overdo all these things but
we get married and we stop dating he was
like no over date your spouse yeah over
date so just do the most yeah do the
most and we put so much I'm going back
to the kid thing but it doesn't have to
be kids it could be work we do we put so
much into these other things work trying
to make a lot of money or whatever you
know just other things like it's okay to
do those things okay it's okay to be an
awesome mother and father and parent to
you you should be an awesome mother and
father parent to your children it's okay
to you know do make money and have like
things that you know different work
different things that you do for your
job you know different
um streams of income that you might do
it's all fine but put that much energy
into your spouse as well yeah
um
yeah also I mean look at that third
commandment you know did I take the name
of the Lord in vain just translate that
it's basically the Commandment is saying
don't take the Lord in vain right same
thing for your spouse right don't don't
take your spouse for granted
right don't just don't ever call them
out of their name yeah don't assume do I
mean and don't in other words don't
I shouldn't say assume but don't
treat them with that respect right right
don't take them for granted like they're
they're already here you're married to
me so I yeah with me because
because but yeah yeah your spouse can
get up and leave like you know so what I
when you're looking at these
Commandments try to glean those
principles from the Commandments and
apply them to your to your marriage
right
um when you know we talk about thou
shall not kill like what about marriage
killers
yes what about romance Killers yes right
and I say don't kill their Spirit yeah
your spouse's Spirit like you know like
by saying things that that are unkind
and basically what about communication
but saying unkind things that kill their
Spirit those are love Killers yeah right
those are relationship Killers so I'm
ignoring you
um I'm you know what I'm saying I I
I speak ill of you
um
I love you to you to you all these
things are romance Killers marriage
Killers uh be aware of that
right marriage Killers might be
different in every marriage like what is
it that kills your spouse's love for you
that you know like makes it very
difficult don't do those things right do
your best
to take that that commandment and say
you know I'm not gonna uh I'm not gonna
do anything that's going to
uh injure or kill the love in our
marriage to let the fire go out to let
that fire the fire to go out yep verbal
abuse
[Music]
um
and you know someone's saying you know
their spouse only makes time for them in
the bedroom again that's Candlestick
Focus right that's Candlestick Focus
right it's and it's a it's a and it's a
false and it's a false it's a false case
it's not focused because the fire is not
if you're just focused on it's not real
if you haven't done all the others it's
not real and you may think it's real but
if there's no communication if there's
no there's no healthy education uh
emotional intimacy if there's no
um uh forgiveness then remember these
articles of furniture were never
designed to work alone it's a system
so if you think about you know uh you
buy someone from the store and it's a
machine all parts of the machine have to
be working for the machine to work
properly right yeah one part of it shuts
down
um yeah you're not it's just like a car
yeah if you have the charge battery but
the alternator is not working it doesn't
get in the engine anyway at all
everything everything has to work has to
work together so imagine those articles
of furniture in the diagram I show you
imagine them like spinning that means
they're working if if five of them are
spinning then one isn't
yeah
if one of them is spinning and five
isn't right that you got issue you got
an issue you have to fix what's not
working in order for everything to work
together yes
um so yeah think about those things with
the law of God like okay uh you know I'm
not gonna uh I'm going to try to take
these Commandments and apply them to my
marriage to keep my marriage
uh
truthful pure
strong
balance all of it be honest uh with your
spouse always and be transparent
yeah yeah be transparent sometimes I
mean some people think like oh I'm being
honest with my spouse but they're not
transparent
um a marriage should be two people being
transparent with each other yeah
um always
always it's you know I think there was a
question a few weeks ago about you know
are there any things you can keep secret
this is not you losing your
individuality like you're still an
individual and do you know you do what
you love to do and you know he he or she
does what they like to do but being
honest with your spouse and being
transparent or being transparent is so
crucial uh to the marriage very very
crucial to the marriage yeah
um so I mean
I think
if we can take these things everything
that we've learned over the last so
we've done is it seven
uh we did one for each article of
furniture and then with the Candlestick
I think we did too
so I think it's seven all together it
might be eight I'm not sure but if we
can look at all these principles right
and start practicing them and
you know is it gonna happen overnight
it's not
but you have something an actual plan
that you can start working on afterwards
working towards and just give yourself
um really quick before I go there we
didn't say covet only your spouse I mean
that's again that should be a given that
you only covet your spouse and nobody
else
um so that's self-explanatory but
um you know giving yourself practical
small goals
that you know you can achieve is what's
going to keep you going and keep you
encouraged to keep moving forward
instead of doing this lofty like I am
going to
do all the the you know pieces six
pieces of furniture
tomorrow yeah that's pretty lofty you
know that's pretty and and and the
probability that you could not and you
fail and then you'll get discouraged and
not want to do it anymore but if you set
before yourself small little tiny
achievable goals
and then you'll be encouraged like okay
I can do that and then you move on to
the next and then you get more
encouraged and you move on to the next
and you just you know you're you're
really
um gonna Encourage Yourself remember the
sanctuary service wasn't designed to be
accomplished in one day right it was
every day
it was a process every day they were
they were getting into the habit and we
talk about
you know the whole idea of
neuroplasticity and how you could change
your your thoughts and that's what we're
trying to do or we're all the centuries
in essence teaching us how to think
differently yes how to approach things
differently this is you're changing your
mind like neuroplasticity is happening
yeah neuroplasticity is happening right
in real time and and the the foundation
of that is very simply that
the sanctuary is a picture of the mind
of Christ
right the sanctuary is a picture of the
mind of Christ it shows you Christ's
thought pattern of self-sacrificing love
right of empathy of forgiveness that's
what you're seeing
you're looking at the mind of Christ
and so in looking at the mind of Christ
the Bible says by beholding we become
changed so the more we behold these
articles of furniture and study what
each article the thoughts that each
article represents because that's what
it is
each article represents the thought of
self-sacrifice and the thought of
forgiveness and the thought of
communication the thought of empathy
empathy the thought of physical intimacy
all of these things as we learn to think
this way our minds are being changed and
we are being transformed into the image
of Christ right yes no completely I kind
of want to speak to the couple who or
somebody in the situation not even just
somebody but
um because I want to bring this up
before but just speak to you know a lot
of times there are situations that and
really all of us and I spoke about this
a couple weeks ago too that you know we
all are you know we were like I've worn
my you know and I we were raised by
completely totally different parents we
were raised in two different situations
so when we decided to get married and
come together we're bringing uh you know
our upbringing the way we were raised
what the good things and the bad things
we're bringing that uh into the marriage
and and for some people you know you're
bringing you know trauma and different
issues of that nature uh unresolved
trauma I should say because we've all
experienced some levels of trauma
throughout our life but unresolved not
healed trauma into the marriage and that
in itself is causing you know conflict
and issues
um and so there's many times where
couples will come in and say we want to
work on these things and have a Chicago
a glory experience but
sometimes
we refer them for individual therapy
because people individually need to work
on those uh on those traumas and those
hurts and those pain and that pain and
then come back together uh and then work
on the marriage and that can be a
successful situation so
um many times I should say many but
there are times when that is you know
the case where that needs to happen
personal healing needs to happen and
even if you don't have individual
therapy and then come back still if
you're you know you know you need to
work on your marriage a lot of times
individual healing needs to happen yeah
uh for the marriage to be successful
amen amen because it's causing a a lot
of different problems just trying to
catch some of the questions
um
I don't know I might have missed some of
them
um in comments but so why are you
looking for those questions
um I know that many of you have uh
requested that
this series which we're now complete so
it's now a complete series right be put
together
um you know kind of separated from the
Divine service and put together just as
a series on marriage right so you can
share it yeah and we're working on that
right yep okay so actually it's already
on the uh it should be up on the YouTube
channel now as a series uh we're gonna
add this this is the final today's and
then uh if you guys want to share
this as a series to people that you know
that may be going through some some
matter issues whether they are Christian
or not non-Christian right and they're
open to getting help
um this is going to be a powerful way to
in essence share the gospel yes because
this is the gospel we're just making it
applicable to uh relationships right uh
so yeah this will be available
um and we will you know you'll be able
to share it with as many people as as
you want to so yeah um
look out for it yes look out for it and
if there was okay a question but I think
it was just a
um a statement or a comment to somebody
else okay yes definitely uh um share
this information it is
as we said 50 of marriages end up in
divorce that's a huge huge number I
there's no one I I like will not believe
that there's somebody that's watching
right now uh that are or will watch
later that has not been impacted does it
have to be your parents but impacted by
divorce in some way or the other
um I think everybody has been impacted
by that and so you know we want to again
God created marriage and he created
marriage to be you know we know that we
live in a simple world but he still
wanted marriage to uh marriages to stay
together and to be healthy and so uh
learning the principles on how to be
able to do that his way to be able to do
that is in the sanctuary yeah and so um
we have tried to provide practical
applications of the Articles of
furniture and a practical way to your
marriage and so now it is your time or
your turn to apply it hopefully you've
been applying it but it's it's now time
to apply the things that you have
learned so you can have a better
marriage and definitely share with your
friends and family as well yeah and tell
them you learned about it right here on
living managers uh the name of the
series is marriage and the sanctuary
solution
so marriage and the sanctuary Solution
that's uh that's where that's what you
look for and you'll find the playlist on
the uh YouTube channel yes
um all right well yeah I think we
covered everything that we wanted to
cover never we never have enough time
but it was you know by God's grace it is
the information that you that you will
need to move forward
um we're praying that you will remain
with us as we continue our worship
service uh today and I want to um
because I didn't say this at the
beginning of Sabbath school but invite
you to participate in alter live which
is the after glow after the sermon that
is where we form community that is where
um we just connect that is and so
download it that right there it's in the
chat so download uh alter live if you
haven't done so and if you've never
visited but you hear us making these
announcements every week visit you will
not regret visiting altar live after it
is truly a time where you can connect
hear people's voices you can even see
them but you don't have to and you don't
have to speak either you can still put
things in the chat because there's a
chat there as well uh but it is where
you know testimonies are heard how the
sermon or everything that you learned
today impacted you it is is an
encouragement
um prayer request our May there and
there's a prayer time as well so it's
just a wonderful wonderful experience so
join us in altar live after the sermon
yeah we should also mention that um uh
let's see if you want to get alerted uh
for
um
things going on with uh living mana and
you want to get on our text messaging
app uh you see it right there you want
to text the letters lmoc to the number
84576 right so if you're trying to text
someone a number and you put in their
whole number that's the number you're
putting in it's not a whole number it's
just those eight four five seven six
they're going to text the word lmoc and
you'll get a notification and you will
then be on our uh text mailing list if
you will right you'll get alerts of when
we have different programs coming up
um and like yes yes when they're coming
up it'll remind you like for mental
health Mondays it will remind you uh on
Monday that that's happening everything
what we're doing on Tuesday and
Wednesday and Thursday and then for
church as well we'll also send different
announcements if you need to know
something that we didn't mention here or
it's just a really what great way for us
to communicate with you for you to stay
up to date with what living matter
church is doing and you want to stay
connected yeah
and uh let me also mention that for the
Divine service I'm going to be speaking
on the subject of Law and Grace and uh
listen guys don't I'm just gonna say
this like invite people
uh we put sent out a text yesterday and
just let it let it be known that uh
every last Sabbath of the month is going
to be uh truth sharing Sabbath so I'm
going to be dealing with a specific
Doctrine right whether it's a state of
the dead or or Hellfire or the Sabbath
or what have you uh today is going to be
on the law of God should it be kept or
should Christians keep the law of God or
not has it been done away with and uh
you're going to learn some things that
you may not have have uh understood
before so yeah don't miss this good
sharing tools yeah for you yeah as well
yeah so uh with that uh I think we're
gonna go ahead and put prayer okay and
um and then we'll see you in the divine
stay tuned don't go anywhere let's pray
Heavenly Father we thank you for giving
us this opportunity Lord to speak to the
marriage question Lord and um Lord I
just pray that you would
um bless uh every marriage Lord that
attempts to take your way and and and
seek to become stronger uh seek to heal
Lord marriages that may be dead that you
can bring back to life Lord I pray your
blessing upon every one of them I pray
your blessing upon everyone listening
everyone who will watch in the future
Lord
um May this tool may your Sanctuary
Service uh show them the way uh to true
love to True at one minute and we thank
you Lord for hearing and answering
um bless us now as we begin prepare to
enter into our divine service in Jesus
name we pray amen amen
foreign
[Music]
of all the trees in the Kingdom of the
plants there's one that stands out from
all the rest in some parts of the world
this tree is venerated even worshiped as
deity in other parts of the world it is
seen as a natural jungle gym just
waiting to be explored
it is the home of many birds a shade for
weary Travelers and a natural playground
for The Children of Men
of all the trees on God's green earth
the mighty Banyan is definitely one of
my favorites now there are several
things that make this tree truly unique
the Bold Banyan begins its life by
growing off of and deriving nutrients
from another tree this tree is called
the host tree
the mighty Banyan sends down roots from
its branches all around the host tree
over time it completely overtakes the
territory of the host tree and cuts off
its supply of sunlight it's like the
Banyan completely swallows up the host
tree and the Hoshi forever becomes a
part of the Banyan once the roots of the
Banyan hit the soil and become well
grounded it then grows into strong
trunk-like structures that support the
quickly extending branches of the Banyan
thus enabling the branches to spread out
far and wide it looks like a large
system of multiple interlocking trees
and yet it is only one singular tree
as I walked into the shade of the mighty
Banyan and climbed upon its sturdy
branches I couldn't help but think of
the many spiritual lessons this tree
teaches us
you see the Bannon is able to live
because of the host tree that gave up
its life and just as the whole street
dies so that the Banyan Tree might live
so too there's one that died so that we
might live forever Jesus died on the
tree of the Cross so that we might have
life Everlasting but the Banyan Tree
takes away life only to give it back in
Rich fruit so too we derive our life
from our creator that we might share it
with those around us at once we are
rooted and grounded in Christ we're then
called to Bear the fruit of the spirit
to the glory and the honor of his name
the unique root system of the Banyan
tree is also reminded to us of the
ultimate roof Jesus The Book of
Revelation calls him the root of David
the bride and Morning Star
although the root is the most unsightly
part of the plant it is also the most
powerful it not only sustains Life by
bringing nutrients to the branches and
leaves of the tree but it also holds up
the massive weight of the tree massive
rocks and concrete slabs are torn apart
by the noiseless power of the root
hidden beneath the soil its power is
mighty and so too the power of the root
of David hidden in the heart can break
the strongest bands of sin it is the
root of David Jesus Christ that gives us
life and holds us up as Trees of
Righteousness light tree roots he's not
always seen or noticed but surely he is
there and by the power of that Divine
root we shall be able to withstand all
the storms of the enemy for the Bible
says that the root of the righteous
shall not be moved
[Music]
so today I encourage you let Christ be
the root and Foundation of your life and
as you do you will become a
fruit-bearing shelter in this unsafe and
starving World a strong solid sturdy and
stable sanctuary of Refuge for others
and with strong roots and sweet fruits
you will be just like Jesus who sent his
roots down from Heaven to Earth that we
might be forever connected just like a
Heavenly Banyan Tree to our wonderful
God above
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
by this new reflections of Hope episode
this episode is one of many that's been
produced all over the world if you
haven't done so yet please give our
video a like share it with your friends
and please follow us on Instagram
Facebook and YouTube if you'd like to
see more inspiring episodes and get
access to much more uplifting content
please go now to patreon.com forward
slash revelation of Hope and sign up to
be a member of our patreon page your
monthly support will not only give you
early access to many more inspiring
videos but it will also enable us to
continue to produce more of these
cinematic object lessons from nature our
goal is to produce and release these
episodes much more frequently so please
prayerfully consider partnering with us
so that we may continue to share the
hope of Jesus all over the world thank
you so much for your support Aloha and
Maranatha
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
foreign foreign
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
living Mana church family we are so
happy that you have continued uh to
worship with us some of you may have
just joined and did not join during our
Sabbath School discussion so please put
in the chat where you are watching from
if you have not already done that we
want to say a special welcome to you and
when you're saying where you're from if
you put a one for a fir you're a first
time visitor we especially want to know
if this is your very first time also if
you have prayer requests those who have
attended living man in church or in our
our normal
visitors and members here
um you all already know that brother
Terry and the prayer team are are
collecting your prayer request and some
of the requests will be prayed over
during this Divine worship service so
please put in the uh chat your prayer
request so that the prayer team can pray
over your request they collect all the
prayer requests and they they pray over
each and every one even if it doesn't
get prayed over during this during this
service it will be prayed over uh during
the week so please put your prayer
request in the chat and so we welcome
from New Jersey
um we see New Jersey is is here with us
someone from New Jersey also South
Carolina
welcome to Texas Houston Texas we used
to call that we used to call Houston
Texas our second home
um New Jersey
yes welcome
um South Carolina
did you say South Carolina okay okay I
saw South Carolina uh welcome welcome
welcome from Los Angeles from California
yes another from California Freeport
Trudy Brown Freeport I grew up in
Freeport yes I saw that California so
amen Freeport
um Alberta Canada Florida
yes welcome welcome it is always
wonderful to see where everyone is
watching from another one from New
Jersey Barbados
never been to Barbados never been no I
want to go there someday and Johnny for
the first time so welcome
yes we have a one where was the one it
was uh at Eglin I believe the hopefully
I pronounced that right yeah where was
Johnny for the first time from Barbados
from Barbados wonderful wonderful
welcome a special welcome to you
um since it's your first time and then
others can hear this again but we have
an after uh after glow after the sermon
so we invite you to uh download the app
that's gonna go in the chat right now on
Ultra live that's in the chat right now
so you can join uh the after uh after
discussion after glow it is truly a
bless it is like the cherry on top of
the of the Sabbath worship experience
so we encourage everyone uh to do that
and really get to know your living Mana
church family that way prayer happens in
there as well and testimonies
um it's just truly truly a blessing and
you know we mentioned this at during
Sabbath School time too but we are
in the works and planning for our
Outreach for living Mana Church to start
their physical Outreach because I know
you guys share these links and share
these messages and that's we want you to
continue to do that that's amazing but
we truly need to go out into the
community and become the Feats and the
feet in hand I should say of Jesus and
so we really want to get that going and
so please stay tuned for more
information about that because uh
you you will really want to be partaking
in that and as you see all the different
places that we have around Argentina wow
welcome hola Feliz that's a little
that's a little Spanish I know welcome
that's definitely the first from
Argentina sorry but you see we have
people in Argentina and Barbados and and
I just saw one pop up from the UK in
London so we're all around the world
that's what living matter church is
we're all around the world
um and we need to go out into our
individual communities and meet the
needs of those in our communities and so
that is what you know that's another
part of what this church is all about
you know we want to do the entire gospel
and be practical with it and Reach
people so that is coming so definitely
stay tuned uh for that and we need to
say that we after we're going to talk
about ways that you guys can give and
support uh the ministry but after that
we have a special guest that's going to
be be here so you're going to want to
stay tuned for that as well because it's
really the information that will be
shared will be a blessing as well yeah
but I want to let you guys know how you
can support living matter Church there's
you know several ways uh to be able to
do that first you can go to
adventistgiving.org and put in living
matter church but an even easier way
than that is you could go to our website
at livingmanna.church click on tithe and
offering and that will take you to
Adventist giving and you will be able to
give your tithe and your offering there
there's a virtual envelope you just it
the tide line is first I think there's
an example of it the timeline is first
and then the local uh get the the local
church giving for the offering is second
and so you're able to to give your tithe
and offering there your tithe goes to
support the northeastern conference uh
which this church is a part part of and
so that helps to support that conference
in the worldwide Church of The
Seventh-Day Adventist Church and then if
you are wanting to give something to
living managed Church directly to
support what we do here each and every
week than you give to our local church
budget and that helps to support living
matter Church also you can do that you
can give your offering by going to cash
app it's dollar sign living at a church
you can scan that QR code that you see
there and you'll be able to give that
way as well and finally you can do the
traditional way and you can just mail in
your tithe and offering to living Mana
church that's at P.O box
428 Owens Crossroads Alabama
35763 and when you do it that way you
just need to Mark what is tithe and what
is offering so we can make sure that it
goes to the right place and so those are
the ways that you can give and you guys
have been very faithful in supporting
the church through your prayers through
your financial givings and we just
really want to say thank you and how
much we appreciate it I always say that
this was an idea a prayerful idea of his
and God well I feel like the Holy Spirit
put it on your heart and then you pray
like okay God if you want this to happen
then you need to make it allow it to
happen and he has allowed it to happen
and the Holy Spirit and God have just
been working has brought us extremely
talented people to work with us and
we're so very thankful
our board members all of those who
participate in our weekly
programs that we do all throughout the
week even the technical support behind
uh the scene like you guys think Patrice
is just the Church secretary she's not
she's the technical uh Guru behind some
of these things we have brother Fred
that assist
um you know it's just it's amazing how
God has brought everything together and
so we are just thankful for your
financial support your prayers the team
everyone who helps to support the
ministry each and every week to make it
happen and let me mention very quickly
uh of course people are asking how do
they become members of living matter
um there there are two ways if you are
if you're wanting to transfer your
membership you would contact uh Patrice
at Living Mana dot live
um and that should be going up in the
chat too or we'll scroll across if not
in the chat it will scroll across the
screen
um
yeah here soon yes
if if you uh have never been baptized
before and you want to become a member
of the living Mana online Church uh
through baptism uh you would uh reach
out to uh to Rick uh Dingman and
um Rick what can we put up his email
address as well just in case those
um if you want to join
uh through baptism you have not been
baptized before you would contact Rick
or you can contact Patricia Shield get
it over send it yeah so those are the
two ways in which uh we can either
you're either transferring your
membership
right you may have been baptized before
but not into
um The Seventh-Day Adventist Church and
you want to become a member uh you don't
necessarily have to be baptized again
you can just join by profession of Faith
again uh either Patrice or or Rick and
um yeah just use that email that's
scrolling across your screen and your
email will get directed to the right
place yep for sure for sure
but we just want to say a prayer over
the the offering that has in the tithe
that has been given today and I know
that they you give all throughout the
week as well but we just want to do a
prayer of Thanksgiving just thanking
everyone for their faithfulness and just
for God to God for all that he does for
this church and Ministry would you pray
for us please uh Heavenly Father we just
uh pause for a woman to thank you for
the faithful giving not only of members
Lord but even of visitors Lord people
that are just supporting this ministry
um supporting the vision Lord we pray
that you would bless them
um as they give Lord we pray
that as a church Lord we might be able
to reach every corner of this globe Lord
that we will be able to get into homes
Lord without even having to knock Lord
um you have provided technology really
for such a time as this Lord and we just
pray that you would help us to use it to
our best ability uh in your strength
Lord thank you again for those that that
are giving for those that are praying
um and supporting uh supporting in any
way in every way that they can Lord
um please just just bless all this is
our prayer in Jesus name amen amen amen
yes amen and at this time we said we
have a special guest we want to bring in
our special guest at this time hello and
welcome welcome to living management
yes
yes wait we can't hear you oh okay I was
muted sorry there we go there we go yeah
happy stabbing happy Sabbath I have to
say I love your hair wrap I love the
color too thank you it's very pretty do
you see do you see people are losing
their minds right now they're like all
right you know I get distracted if I
look at them
they're like what who no yeah that's the
kind of
yeah that's the kind of response you're
getting yeah
we're so happy to have you here
um yeah so we want you to tell us about
your ministry and what you do and and
just just for those of you that that
don't know uh you know Sister Neff and I
we go back how long uh 18 months
something like that I think it's longer
than that I say all of coveted is more
than was it before it was that before it
was during covet it was it's at least
two going on tonight yeah
yeah yeah and uh she reached out to to
me and a couple others Dwayne
um lemon and um Lance Wilbur and uh we
ended up doing a whole series uh called
the make it uh plane series and uh it's
uh really reached a lot of people
so I don't know if you want to share a
little bit about that and then you could
like get into you know what you're doing
now we wanted to bring you on because
you you're doing something in the church
that not a lot of people do or know how
to do so go ahead and talk to us about
that and if you want to again just kind
of talk about how we connected that
would be great so go ahead Okay cool so
thanks again for having me um so I've
been doing uh Ministry on social media
for about six years
um and I was pretty much walking in a
network working with a network of people
who were it was kind of like an
interdenominational thing so each person
had their own Ministry but we'd often
collaborate and whatnot
um and then
like two and a half years into that
networking the issue of me being
seven-day Adventist came up
and there was a huge Fallout
um I was basically like actually not
basically literally they put out a
statement
anathematizing me and the Adventist
Church uh you guys have to excuse my
voice I'm going through changes
um but so there was a statement issue
that was shared widespread among social
media saying I'm listing a bunch of
doctrines that administ supposedly
believe
um and that were condemnable and
therefore the entire Adventure
nomination myself included should be
avoided so that's why I reached out to
pastors lemon and Ivor and Lance to kind
of correct the misinformation that was
being uh spread about the church uh not
so much about me but about the church
like and the issue was the people who
were in the leadership within that
Network weren't willing to hear
basically the fact that what they were
saying was misrepresentation so it's one
thing to disagree with Adventist
Doctrine but it's another thing entirely
to disagree with something you made up
and ascribe that to adventism right and
so that's that's what birth the make it
series our intent was to make it plain
from scripture alone what is it that
Adventists believe
um and it was a series of about 32
videos that we did and it was it was a
huge blessing a lot of people who were
unfamiliar with adventism or the Sabbath
or any of the uh beautiful adoptions
that we hold were exposed for the first
time and I praise God for it
intended as an ambassadment for me
wounded up to being to God's glory and
there were people who were got have
gotten baptized out of that yeah yes yes
yeah yeah it's blessing so what are you
in your what are you doing now what is
your minutes what are you doing now with
your ministry so I've just continued the
work that I'd already been doing okay
and if we could share the the slides
that I had yeah it's like eight or nine
slides I'll I'll move quick
so here's my mission statement and this
has been my mission statement throughout
the entirety which is to help you feel
secure in your Christianity while being
black to help you feel secure in your
Blackness while being Christian and then
to do my part to hasten his coming
um so I find that oftentimes
people are put in a position to kind of
have to choose whether or not they're
going to walk in their ethnicity or be
Christian but and there are certain
areas where there's a conflict but where
there is not a conflict between can I
interrupt you for a second sure so some
people may not even understand the
context of that but in the
African-American Community especially in
the younger African-American community
Christianity in a sense is like
it's like no I'm not that because that
is The White Man's religion and that's
how they view it and that's what's going
around kind of like you know hip-hop
circles just that young uh generation
and so much of your ministry is to kind
of dispel that myth that Christianity
and being black don't go together right
correct correct so that would be the
first thing right the first line to help
you feel secure in your Christianity
because Christianity is often attacked
right on the basis of what you just said
that it's the quote-unquote slave
masters religion and then people find
themselves in
um in a position of like confusion right
and then the second portion is again if
there's a cultural difference between
scripture and what we've grown up doing
like for example I'm just using an
example like yelling at your kids a lot
of times that's a cultural thing that's
at odd with the gospel we shouldn't be
yelling at our kids so even though we
grew up doing that we need to put that
to the side but in other instances
expression of your nationality or
ethnicity is not a sin right and so
um I I help find that balance right to
keep Christ first but not necessarily
shun your ethnic identity and so I
helped to answer questions that are
uniquely related to being an
African-American or afro-descendant
um and so that it will remove stumbling
blocks from people who who want or who
otherwise might consider joining the
faith or who are in danger of leaving
Christianity because of some of the
myths that are being spread so
um so here are some of the topics that I
cover uh true Christianity true biblical
Christianity is at the Forefront uh
traditional African religions and
African spirituality which is another
thing that's becoming very popular it's
um a sort of spiritualism that claims
Africa as it root at its root and
therefore Lords people on the strength
of it being African and so I do a lot of
discussion on that
um Christianity and American slavery
um the truth behind how American slaves
were exposed to Christianity uh
Christianity and ancient Africa Hebrew
israelism I know Pastor Myers is
something that you also address a big
big thing that's kind of threatening to
pull a lot of people away from Christ
because in some circles not all of them
but in some Hebrew Israelite circles
they deny the deity of Christ they put
an over emphasis on Race
um and things of that nature and then
also modern witchcraft are some of the
things that I talk about so on my um and
one of my presentations that I did
specifically for Adventist congregation
I found this research on um on peel
research which basically says that
Seventh-Day Adventists are among the
most racially and ethnically diverse
religious groups in America so that
doesn't account necessarily for the rest
of the world right um and so it says 37
are white while 32 are black now if you
look at the the bars here these are
other denominations and you see the
first bar representing white or European
American is the dominant bar but when
you get down to Seventh-Day Adventists
where the arrow is pointing it's a lot
more even because it represents African
Americans yeah right so we have a lot of
African-Americans within our
denomination and therefore a lot of
people who grapple with some of the
questions that I address in my Ministry
yeah here are some of the titles of
videos that I've done black lives matter
the organization and their affiliation
with ancestors sister worship which a
lot of people aren't familiar with I I
dug it up and I was very shocked myself
um why I left African spirituality
because I was raised partially Catholic
and also in African spirituality and
then during my teen years I went into
egyptology which is known as Comet so I
did a video on that
um Hebrew israelism what makes an
Israelite an Israelite according to
scripture and how you know by faith we
are Abraham's seed right and heirs
according to the promise
um I talk about Constantine I talk about
Beyonce and her African spirituality and
then God of our ancestors is a YouTube
series that talks about slave narratives
from America and how they were converted
it's a very powerful series because we
hear from their own words oftentimes
what happened to them
um in their efforts to follow Christ so
here's one example from my Facebook page
it says that slaves were killed for
having church just going to read this
really quick it says my wife's brother
so this was written by someone who was
formerly enslaved in America
it says my wife's brother Isaac was a
colored preacher
a number of slaves went privately into
the wood to hold meetings when they were
found out so that word meetings means we
were having Church
um and it says when they were found out
they were flogged and each was forced to
tell who else was there
[Music]
and the other was badly wounded for
preaching to them Isaac's flocked and
his back pickled when he was nearly well
it was clogged and pickled again and so
on for some months then his back would
suffered to get well and he was sold so
this is just one example of how people
often repeat this myth that the slave
master somehow forced Christianity upon
the slaves under the threat of violence
or what I've been finding for the past
five years time and time again is that
the complete opposite is true they were
threatened under penalty of debt to stay
away from prayer to keep away from Jesus
and then only a few years before
emancipation is when they started to
introduce slavery on Christianity to
Slaves withholding certain parts of the
Bible and kind of trying to mold their
version of Christianity that they wanted
us to know
and then specifically within adventism
the types of presentations I do the
Sabbath in ancient Africa Christianity
slavery and the millerite movement I
found that the Miller Right Movement had
reached even unto the slaves and it's
just it's a beautiful reading their
accounts not Adventist this is not
Adventist sources these are just regular
slave narratives where we find that the
millerite movement reached them
and then the SDA church and black
history we have a rich culture of
History especially when it comes to
abolition and equality and how God sees
us as human beings and it's just it's
it's really beautiful especially
considering
um as a defender of the faith how people
often misrepresent our Founders as
having been racist when you write up
what you had to say about race and how
God views it it gives you
um so here's one of them uh this is
taken from testimonies volume nine it
says let the colored laborers do what
they can to keep abreast working
earnestly for their own people I thank
God that among the colored Believers
there are men of talent who can work
efficiently for their own people
presenting the truth in clear lines so
one thing I'm going to leave it there
but one thing that I gathered from this
quote was this was the courage and the
strength to continue ministering to
afro-descendants because she says to
work for your own people now doesn't
mean exclusively it doesn't mean anybody
else but it recognizes that there are
certain needs because of our condition
our historical condition there are
certain things that are you know tended
to by you know people who of similar
circumstance
and then finally I'm only going to read
the highlighted portion here but if you
want the whole quote you can go to early
writings
275. but sister white says that angel
said to her it will be more more
tolerable for the Heathen and for
papists in the day of the execution of
God's judgment then for some Earth and
the men who are slave holders
so then it says the names of the
oppressors are Written in Blood crossed
with stripes and flooded with agonizing
burning tears of the suffering God's
anger will not cease until he has caused
this land of light to drink of the dregs
of the cup of his Fury until he has
rewarded unto Babylon double and this is
being said with regards to people who
call themselves Christian and hold
slaves this history right yeah
so that so that's basically what I do
and then on my Facebook page again my
mission is to help Payson is coming so
I've been putting out a lot of content
regarding the reformers and how they
felt about who the Beast and the
Antichrist was and it would be great if
anybody who was on Facebook would join
and just share and join the conversation
to help people know because we gotta
hasten the Lord's coming you know we got
to do our part work all right here's how
you can follow me the first two are the
most important my email and Facebook
yes yes please
take note of those of how you can follow
an effort and how you can get more
information that is some really powerful
stuff that's some really powerful stuff
can you say I mean I just had a question
really quick
um and even if we could put her
information up there because I don't
know if it was up there long enough to
go back to how people can okay and we
can stay small let that information stay
um
were you saying so
the the millerite uh the movement and
the and the message that they had had
reached the slaves
um what like what what article are you
or where are you pulling that
information from I'm just curious It's
so it's so beautiful anytime I'm reading
a secular source and I find just it's
like a Hidden Gem of something related
to our history our church history so I
was doing what I usually do
reading through the slave narratives
looking for religious content looking
for conversions and I saw
excuse me
I saw that a slave had said that William
Miller's Doctrine about the soon coming
of Christ had reached their area and it
was all anybody could talk about and
then it said that the the quotation goes
on to say in this narrative that it
broke down the system of cast and class
that slave owners and slaves were
conversing with one another as though
slavery were not in existence because
this was on the soon coming of Christ
wow yeah yeah wait can well we we have
your numbers so you're gonna text us
that information yeah it was definitely
I meant it to you I want to read that
yeah wow that's that's very powerful yes
yes yeah
man that's good stuff
um so Nev your your are you uh traveling
and speaking at churches is that uh
something that you're you're doing or is
everything you're doing strictly online
um no I do both so I'm Every Day I'm
online and then I take calls as I get
them to go to churches or to present
um for Ministries online in their Zoom
meetings
um within I'm presenting the variety of
topics that I've listed right
um so yeah I'm available to go to
churches and talk to their youth as
especially like you said like these
questions regarding you know uh racial
history or African spirituality or
witchcraft are particularly of Interest
not you know it's to everybody but
particularly to young people because
they're the ones who who get caught up
in the trends and things of that nature
so I love to present to to you
especially we're trying to get you down
here to to Oakland I think she would be
phenomenal down here I would love to do
that yes we're going to work on that
we're gonna make that happen yeah also
just to let you know yes
never will be on a freestyle Wednesday
already been talking about it yes we
have yeah
and for the yes Dwayne and Lance the
four of us together we're gonna do one
yeah so just uh uh just know what's
gonna happen okay it's gonna happen
we're working on a date to figure out
when we when our calendars all mesh and
we'll be able to do it so
yes it will happen you know yeah thank
you again and if we could just put her
information up again just us but thank
you again
what you are doing
um just wow that that was some powerful
stuff you shared just in that that short
amount of time so we definitely want to
have you back here on living mana and um
yeah we're gonna try to get you to
Oakwood University where you have
thousands of young people that you could
definitely uh minister to to they would
love to hear your information
praise God thank you I look forward to
it and I appreciate you guys having me
on today again I'm sorry about my voice
it's the craziest thing because I
believe like it's spiritual
um I hadn't been doing Ministry for a
while focusing on my health and whatnot
and my voice was perfectly normal up
until last week when I shared this post
about
uh what was it the Ethiopian no
Egyptians Coptic Christians having kept
the Sabbath for the first few centuries
and persuasion changing things in that
nature and then I was intending to go
live and my voice started tripping and
it's been like this since then it's just
it's mind-blowing to me but yeah
please yeah
yeah by the way if if any of you have
not if they're those of you who are like
what make it plain series I never saw
that what are you talking about
um we're gonna
I don't know someone can put a link in
the chat
um either on your YouTube page netflow
or they can go to my YouTube page but
I've got a playlist
um uh the make it plain play playlist on
the power of the Lamb YouTube page so
it's live changing guys it is I have had
people tell me that um they've walked in
the faith as Adventists for years and
years and still had much to learn
um from the make it plain Series so yeah
yeah
amen amen amen well sis thank you so
much
yeah yeah and uh we will uh yeah we'll
we'll be in touch okay okay and since
I'm gonna send you that slide with that
uh with that quote
alrighty thank you God bless you all
right God bless
all right yeah so I think uh we're gonna
invite oh okay song and then brother
Terry's gonna come up in all right yeah
continue to worship with us
[Music]
there will be mountains
me to decide but how can I expect
[Music]
can't live
I've come too far from where I started
from
nobody told me
[Music]
this far
I've never said that I wouldn't be
trials
[Music]
and I feel the hope is
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
said I can't give enough
[Music]
[Applause]
nobody told me
[Music]
this is
and I don't believe he's taught me this
way
[Music]
amen amen amen come on somebody and give
God praise
if you know that he didn't bring it as
far to leave you give him glory and give
him praise today
what an awesome God we serve
you know Saints um we're becoming
increasingly aware of the great
privilege and the great opportunity that
God has given us to serve him here in
this living manner church ministry and
particularly in The Prayer Ministry we
are so thankful for the Miracles that
God is working and the way he's
answering prayers I want to encourage
you join us for prayer on power
Wednesdays send your prayer requests in
put your prayer requests in the chat and
if you don't do that keep on praying
anyway because God is good and I tell
you we cannot even begin
to uh put a value on on how awesome
prayer is thank you so much for your
prayers for me as we were moving some
things were happening that we knew had
to be gods and things I can't even share
with you so awesome and so powerful keep
praying Saints so powerful and so uh we
thank you we love you uh uh and uh you
know you see me here doing the
intercessory prayer time it is such a
privilege and an honor to to stand in
the gap for God's people but look none
of this in prayer team stuff would work
without the awesome prayer team that God
has assembled behind us you know Sister
Gigi is a great support for me but you
can see them in the chat Sister Pauline
and sister uh uh Liz is there and
brother PJ and all of the the prayer
warriors are there uh uh sister Yoli and
sister Abby and all of them they know I
love to call all of their names but such
an awesome uh prayer team sister Jean uh
uh Gina Joanne Steven and so I just just
want to just thank the prayer team who
worked behind the scenes and are
constantly laboring uh you know all the
time for us and standing in the Gap and
so thank you all so much for your
service
and Saints just want to encourage you
today as we get ready to go before the
throne of grace
know that we have a great awesome and
mighty God I really want to want to just
really take a moment I know we already
thank God for sister net for who is with
us but man praise God for this powerful
message that he's given this sister and
and for you know I was reminded of a
prophecy from Isaiah the where the Lord
says in this mountain he shall the Lord
he will make a the Lord of hosts will
make a unto all people a feast of fat
things and feast of wines on the lease
and fat things full of marrow and of
Wands on the leaves well refined and he
says he will destroy in this mountain
the face of the covering cast over all
people and that the veil that is spread
over all nations God is revealing truth
and we just want to pray that everybody
that's listening and everybody that's on
and that's hearing and hearing this
Sanctuary message and all of the
passionate is doing that God will remove
the veil over their hearts so come with
me as we go to the throne of grace and
and beseech our God
precious father first of all Lord we
just want to lift you up God we want to
magnify you and give you glory and
praise
God we choose today
to worship you
in spite of what we may be going through
we choose to Worship You Lord we choose
to praise you we choose to magnify you
even when we don't understand even with
tears in our eyes and broken hearts God
we choose because you are faithful and
good God somebody listening to they
can't even see that goodness can't even
sense it can't even feel it but Lord
break through the darkness we pray in
the mighty and precious name of Jesus
Christ of Nazareth your son stretch
forth your hand somebody's ready to give
up right now God ready to throw in the
towel we pray O Lord God as the prophet
Michael said Rejoice not against me or
enemy when I sit in darkness when I fall
I shall arise and when I sit in darkness
the Lord shall be a light unto me Lord
be a light to somebody today in Jesus
name and God we preach that we plead
that precious blood upon them around
them between them and the devil that
they might see your goodness but your
word says it is the goodness of Lord
that leadthly to repentance and so we
just praise and bless you today as we
stand in the Gap and Lord we thank you
for this beautiful series of marriage we
thank you for what you're doing with the
sanctuary one confirmation that we're
the generation will see the coming of
the Lord is that Lord you're bringing
their people back to the encampment
around the sanctuary and it's involved
in every area of Our Lives we're
learning your way how you touch our
relationships our homes our finances our
our health our our mind everything Lord
God associated with your way which is
within that Sanctuary thank you for the
mighty principles and the way you're
teaching us and the way you allowing us
to grow up and for these marriages Lord
that are struggling marriage is work
Lord God there's a work to be done but
you have given us the work to do that's
been ordained before the foundation of
the world help us to trust you in your
way God as we apply these principles in
our lives and watch you work miracles
Lord in our homes and in our marriages
and Lord I was as as they were
discussing sister tante and Pastor was
discussing this morning brother Rick
Dingman put a verse in the chat Lord
for men
that if any man whosoever shall look
upon a woman
to lust after her heaven to already
taken her inner heart I kept seeing that
go through the Trap Lord and you laid on
my heart to pray for men with wandering
eyes that continued to look and continue
to lust some of us with those Quantified
Minds that need to be renewed I want to
pray for brothers struggling somebody
watching today been struggling can't
keep their eyes where they ought to be
can't keep their heart focused can't
keep their minds single God I pray in
Jesus name that you reveal to men the
miraculous Miracle working power that
you are able to produce in their lives
when they do things your way when they
could commit to you and surrender to you
and trust in you Lord you have worked
miracles I'm a living witness today
Hallelujah that you can work a miracle
in the mind and restore the Mind Set
Brothers free today in Jesus name oh
Lord and we just want to uh thank you
for those in the chat so there were some
people in the chat that were seeming so
discouraged
one sister is at the point where she
sings she's ready to have a divorce
because she just can't take it anymore
God in Jesus name I know that she's
speaking on behalf of not just herself
but there's the others who are going
through the same thing Lord God ready to
give up ready to throw in the towel Lord
he'll save touch and deliver in Jesus
mighty name we pray Lord God we're
praying for this sister I'm looking for
her name sister Robin Bob Lord bless her
she's ready to get a divorce give her a
Lazarus experience there's folk
listening today Lord God who have given
up on their marriage buried it then
rolled a stone over it's stinking they
don't want nothing else to do with it
God but I pray you take them back to
that place where they stop trusting you
take them back to the place where they
saw their problems and their struggles
as bigger than you God and may they
rolled away that Stony heart and see you
raise it Up in Jesus you can do it God
hallelujah and we thank you and praise
you today for just giving us the
knowledge of your Miracle working power
in these marriages we want to pray for
our young teenager not even 18 years old
his name is Malik and it's believed that
he's being held uh unjustly Lord God
with no evidence and they're waiting
till he turns 18 so they can convict him
as an adult father your word says that
you execute righteousness and judgment
for those who are oppressed and so Lord
we won't Marvel at this matter we know
that you're in control you're doing
something that even we would wonder if
we knew exactly what you're up to God
you're above these things and we pray
for Malik be with him manifest your
presence with him I know you can come
behind Prison Walls I met you there and
so manifest your presence in his life in
a special way in the name of Jesus God
and just give him peace in the midst of
this chaos Lord and God we're praying
for uh uh Michelle and her uh uh uh this
she's had our sisters Michelle Watson
Grant has submitted a prayer request for
a three-year-old Caleb who's having
surgeries Lord God and he's having
seizures rather and and the doctors
don't know why and so father as they're
seeking answers Lord we just pray you
bring Comfort to them and to the parents
Lord as they're dealing with these
situations Lord we know this is
unspeakable uh uh turmoil in their mind
and Chaos everyone that has a child
every parent that has a child hasn't
watched their child suffer and don't
know why oh God in Jesus name we know
that you are touched with the feeling of
their infirmities build an abiding
presence in the room today in Jesus name
we pray God hallelujah and brother Enoch
has two adult children who've left the
church not only is he praying for a
closer walk with you for himself but he
praying Lord bring him back bring them
back lord Jesus I know you can do it
Lord your your love will pursue us to
the ends of the Earth know it by
experience get them Lord in Jesus name
we pray pray for Janice Ferguson Sister
Janice Ferguson that her marriage will
be strong in the Lord God and I uh we
know that these this Series has really
been so enlightening sister tante and
Pastor Myers are so wonderfully and
beautifully uh elaborated on these
Concepts and principles in the sanctuary
and brought in the daily ons and I just
pray that this has been such a rich
reservoir of truth that we can take and
apply to our lives marriage is working
we got a work to do so thank you for
giving us the tools to work with we're
praying for sister Nia ukatu this
morning her prayer request is that you
will revive her spirit today God
Hallelujah Lord she's asking for
personal Revival and I just feel in my
spirit that that's the prayer request of
not just sister Neo okatsu but someone
else needs a Revival today someone else
needs to want to want to know the
passion and the fire of Falling In Love
With Jesus
someone wants to be returned to their
first love Lord your word says if we be
an evil know how to give good gifts to
our children how much more will the
father give the Holy Ghost to them that
ask God filled somebody this morning
baptize them are fresh and Anew anoint
them with the holy ghost power from the
top of their heads to The Souls of their
feet Lord God your word said that the
spirit that raised Christ from the dead
dwell in them you shall Quicken them
even by their mortal bodies even by your
spirit that dwelleth in them let
somebody get a fresh impact this morning
in Jesus name O Lord God and Lord while
you're doing that sometimes it's about
just making room for you to come in so
Lord what we need to move some mess out
the way God help us slide it over and
make room for Jesus make room for you in
our lives and we know you will feel the
house Lord in Jesus name thank you and
God we're praying for family members who
don't know you Lord God today who are
listening we pray that the anointed word
that the pastor sends out on Law and
Grace uh law in the gospel will will
definitely be a a an eye-opener for
families and for somebody listening Lord
by Divine appointment who you have
brought here Lord praying for brother
Antonio who's waiting for a kidney
and God and uh we know you were a doctor
and you're a physician you know you're a
judge and a lawyer we know that Lord
you're able to provide you're the great
provider Jehovah Jireh more than enough
Lord and so we're praying for this
brother Antonio as he's waiting on you
waiting God for a miracle we want to
hear about it right here in Jesus name
and Lord we want to pray for the prayer
warriors who are not officially a part
of the living man of prayer team I see
them out there we see them in the chat
we know there are folk out there praying
always interceding always making
themselves available always on their
knees Lord God I mean Lord we'll be
foolish to think that we're the only
ones you're stirring up and moving but
God We join our faith along with those
prayer warriors wherever they are in and
around the globe God that the name of
Jesus would be lifted up that chains and
shackles will be loose addictions and
bondages and habits and speaking of
habits sister uh there's a sister here
uh her name is Margo she's praying for
her and her children to overcome bad
habits I pray Lord that as she studies
through the uh the the sanctuary and
learns more about neuroplasticity and
the amazing ability that mind has to
heal itself and remap itself and how
your word is able to get in there and
create your word anointed with creative
power can create new Pathways Lord God
that put us on the right track with you
somebody else needs to be healed in
their mind right now today Lord just
hearing that it needs to be loose Lord
God from a shack from a bad habit and
from a bondage Lord we just pray it in
Jesus name bring healing Lord and so we
want to pray also for Jessica G Farrar
her parents are making a big decision
and they need your leading today oh Lord
lead them and guide them direct them may
they hear your voice speaking Lord we're
praying for Laura our precious sister in
her final year of school Lord and she's
discovered that she's pregnant and Lord
and we know that the devil whispering in
her ear tormenting her until that's just
the end of it your life and your career
is derailed this is all it's about but
Lord you're able to turn it around God
we know your able to turn it around
Hallelujah May her faith be in you sin
folk too or the comforter and encourager
and sure this is only the beginning of
something great and something new that
precious thing she's carrying in her
womb Lord good could be a mighty mighty
move a mighty mighty gift to the kingdom
of God I just pray Lord God that you
just give her hope and give our strength
today Lord God don't let her give up
Lord don't let her be overcome by
depression Lord God and other sisters
out there who may find themselves in
similar situation Lord may be single and
maybe pregnant may have made a bad
mistake and a bad decision may have been
impulsive Lord may have given in in a
weak moment Lord God and now I'm feeling
so bad that they can't even hold their
head up Lord lift them up in the name of
Jesus Hallelujah let them know you love
them before the foundation of the world
and that they are your precious gift o
God Hallelujah Lord God raise up your
people today and even when we have
stumbled and Fallen Lord help them to
see and know that your grace is greater
than all our failures Your Grace is
greater than our weaknesses our
stumbling the blood of Jesus is greater
God than every sin God that we have ever
committed and we just need to come to
you draw them to you Lord by your
goodness in Jesus name we pray and Lord
we want to pray also for Tommy Anderson
has a friend who's death he's gone
through surgery to remove brain tumors
and and and and now he's in a coma and
Lord God we just pray Lord God in this
state that you will uh show up Lord God
and show out Lord and do a miracle in
his life Lord God work in his life thank
you for Tommy for coming and bringing
this request and allowing us to
intercede Lord God and Lord in in
closing here today Lord I want to forget
Michael Yoon muyun who wants a a home
renovation send someone to them to help
them to get their home renovated that
they might have safe dwelling want to
lift up Sister Patrice sister Fred who's
working behind the scenes Lord God thank
you for the beautiful work that they do
Lord God and and in the technical uh
difficulties and obstacles that they
have to face making this thing work and
come together we thank you so much thank
you for the board thank you for Dr White
and everybody who's working behind the
scenes Lord God always making this a a
such a beautiful family and such a
beautiful Ministry we just give you
praise we give you glory and we give you
honor and for all the prayer requests
that we missed uh in the chat Lord that
we just didn't see uh we just uh Lord I
pray better let your Saints know that we
will continue to labor as long as you
give us Grace and strength to do so we
just magnify you here and lift you up
thank you for hearing and answering
these prayers Lord Lord we will be
careful
that as we see these answers coming we
will give you all of the praise and all
of the honor and all of the glory
because you are worthy and all God's
people said
amen
[Music]
thank you
love the
Lord with all your heart
[Music]
with all your mind and soul
love her
with all your strength
[Music]
s
if you love me
show me today
[Music]
foreign
love me
[Music]
[Applause]
amen amen if you love me keep my ways
that is a that's a powerful song
that really prepares us for
um the message today and uh today I'm
going to be talking about the law of God
and the question as to whether the
Commandments still stand or are they
done away with and um
if uh you're listening and watching this
for the first time you're going to learn
some things that you may not have
learned before
um because I'm gonna I'm gonna try to
make it plain today that there are a lot
of people that are confused over this
issue because they don't understand the
context remember what I just said they
do not understand the context
so I'm gonna invite you to pray with me
and then we're going to get into this
presentation and uh we're gonna be
looking at some scripture that's going
to give us a definitive answer uh go
ahead and share this link with someone
that you believe needs to see this and
um let's go ahead and pray all right
let's do that now Heavenly Father
we thank you Lord
For Your Love towards us and we thank
you Lord for your desire to see us walk
in truth
and so Lord speak to us now uh show us
your truth from your word is our prayer
in Jesus name we ask it amen and amen
all right
so I want to start with the the uh idea
of the law of God or actually let me let
me do it this way I want to first talk
about the the moral crisis
that we often hear about that is
happening in our nation uh and depending
on where you are in the world in the
world
okay
um you can go online and find any number
of articles
uh talking about the erosion of
America's foundation and usually this is
from the perspective of Christians right
Christians are the ones that are
typically talking about the moral Decay
destroying America I'm just showing you
a couple of Articles here
uh here's one from the uh from Barna
research the end of absolutes America's
new moral code and they're kind of
talking about how you know people are
just making up their own morals right
nothing is absolute anymore
um Christians be cry this all the time
uh we we see another one here sorry
departure from God is cause of America's
moral decline right
um all of these are issues that that we
are facing here's one on the Theology of
of of abortion right
um the Commandment
thou shall not kill Thou shalt not
killing that one is really really I mean
that's a present issue we're dealing
with right now and uh for the Christian
the argument is right the Commandment
says thou shall not kill and and we
ought to obey the word of God and this
is why there's such a moral decline
because no one is listening or obeying
the word of God uh anymore
here you have another one 10 reasons why
it's wrong to take the life of unborn
children and you could see the first one
uh given there and we're just gonna look
at this very quickly is God commanded
thou shall not murder and Exodus chapter
20 is quoted and so
uh it is it is a serious issue right for
Christians that I'm speaking
specifically to Christians today
um I mean everyone is welcome to listen
but the question again is is this what
is the position that a Christian should
take towards the law of God especially
as it relates
to what we call the moral decline that
is happening in the world well let me
suggest to you that while the Christian
world is is you know kind of looking at
how nobody's following God anymore and
you know people are turning their backs
on the Bible people are turning their
backs on on the word of God and coming
up with their own morals may I suggest
that perhaps part of the reason for that
is actually it actually has to do with
Christianity and its position on the
word of God itself
let me say that again
could the reason that that people are
turning away from the word of God and
from uh uh you know God's absolute
morals could the reason be because of
what they are seeing within Christianity
itself
now no that sounds like whoa kind of
harsh but I need you to follow this
because I'm gonna show you something
let's go back to the screen
and I want you to notice what Romans
chapter 2 verse 21
uh through 24 around 24 says notice what
it says here thou therefore which
teaches another
teach us thou not thyself
thou that preaches a man should not
steal does thou steal
thou that says a man should not commit
adultery does thou commit adultery thou
that aborts Idols does thou commit
sacrilege
thou that maketh thy boast of the law
through breaking the law dishonourist
thou God
and now look at this next verse
for the name of God is blasphemed among
the Gentiles through you as it is
written
let me pause for a second
back in Paul's day
Paul was saying listen because of the of
the hypocrisy of
the professed people of God
the Gentiles are blaspheming the name of
God
so let me give you an example of what I
mean
so if we were to ask you know the the
typical Christian okay
um
why should abortion be outlawed and the
response is going to be because the
Commandment says Thou shalt not kill and
why is our country you know going into
more decline oh because they're not
obeying the word of God they're not
obeying the moral absolutes of God you
hear Christians say this without
blinking an eye it's a natural response
right what are they doing that they
shouldn't be doing and the answer is
they are not keeping God's moral law yet
the very same Christians if you turn
around and ask them hey as a Christian
should you keep the Commandments and
they will begin to quote verses like
this notice with me on the screen
Ephesians chapter 2 and verse 8. it says
for by grace are ye saved through faith
and that not of yourselves it is the
gift of God not of works
lest any man should boast now hold on a
second
I I just
I just inquired
why do you think America's on a moral
Decline and the answer was
America's on a moral decline because
they are not keeping the law of God they
are not keeping the moral absolutes of
God and yet when the question is turned
around and asked should you keep the law
as a Christian then all of a sudden
you get a totally different response
ah we're not saved by works we're Saved
By Faith or how about this one
how about this one uh Ephesians chapter
2 and verse 15. uh uh having abolished
in his flesh the enmity even the law of
Commandments contained in ordinances for
the making himself of Twain one new man
so making peace blotting out the
handwriting of ordinances that was
against us which was contrary to us and
took it out of the way nailing it to the
cross and they'll respond listen
we don't have to keep the law because it
was nailed to the cross but I want you
to understand for the secular mind how
confusing that sounds
on one hand
abortions should be outlawed because the
Bible clearly says Thou shalt not kill
it's one of the Commandments and Exodus
chapter 20 is quoted
you guys you Heathen you atheists you
non-believers you Gentiles you you
people that are not of God you need to
keep the law
but when the very same question is posed
to the believer oh the law has been
nailed to the cross
we don't have to keep the Commandments
it's been done away with that's the Old
Testament
so I want you to understand the
confusion and again my question is could
could the reason that the world
has turned away or or does not
acknowledge the law of God is because
the church
does not acknowledge the law of God
wow
while telling the world that the world
needs to acknowledge the law of God
we need moral absolutes we need the law
of God we need God we need people to
understand that God's word does not
change but here's the issue guys because
those two verses that we just read
they they sound like what people say
right like yeah the text clearly says
that we're gonna go back and look at
that
but we got to ask ourselves a question
is the Bible contradicting itself right
is that a fair question would you say
that's a fair question is the Bible
contradicting contradicting itself does
the Bible have a double standard and is
that the reason why Christians also have
a double standard hey Thou shalt not
kill stop abortion or but in the same
breath ah we're not under the law we're
under grace
the law has been nailed to the cross the
law has been done away with that's
confusion
okay so so let's see does the bible
contradict itself well look at Jesus's
own words
Jesus said in Luke 18 20 thou knowest
the Commandments do not commit adultery
do not kill do not steal do not bear
false witness honor thy father and thy
mother so in Jesus's mind the
Commandment still stood how about John
14 21 he that has my Commandments and
keepeth them heal is that loveth me and
he that loveth me shall be loved of my
father and I will love him and manifest
myself unto him so again Jesus seems
clear that the Commandments still stand
notice revelation 22 verse 14 it's the
last book of the Bible and here it says
blessed are they that do his
Commandments
that they may have right to the tree of
life and may enter in through the gates
into the city how about Revelation 12 17
and the dragon that is Satan was Wrath
with the woman which represents the
church and went to make war with the
remnant of her seed which do what keep
the Commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus Christ how about
First John 3 4 whosoever committed sin
transgresses also the law for sin is
what everyone it is the transgression of
the law so
we see here pretty clearly that the law
of God
in some place in the Bible it appears to
stand but in other places we just read
that the handwriting of ordinances was
blotted out that we're not under the law
we're under grace what what's going on
here how about first John 5 2 by this we
know that we love the children of God
when we love God and keep his
Commandments for this is the love of God
that we keep his Commandments and his
Commandments are not Grievous what in
the world is going on let me say this to
you
that I believe that the majority of
Christians are just confused
and I'm not saying that in a mean
derogatory way I'm saying that in a way
that you know there are Christians who
who want to know truth and they can't
make sense of how the Bible in one place
can say the law of God
still stands but in another place it
says we're not under the law and the law
has been nailed to the cross and so in
in in being unable to to mend these two
so that they make sense you'll find them
you'll find a lot of Christians will
jump from one position depending on who
they're talking to to another position
depending on who they're talking so when
they're talking to the world ah the
Bible says Thou shalt not kill and the
law of God is unchangeable and when is
God ever these are not Ten Commandments
these are ten these are not ten
suggestions they're Ten Commandments
right you hear things like that
but you turn around and I see same
Christians do you need to keep the
Commandments and they're like oh no no
no no no the Commandments have been done
away with uh we're not under the old
Covenant anymore we're under the New
Covenant and they're not
these people are not intentionally
trying to be deceptive at least I don't
think I just think that there are a lot
of Christians who don't understand the
context what did I say everyone they
don't understand the context and maybe
it's because they haven't been taught it
maybe it's because they that what
they're hearing from the pulpits is not
making sense but they're just going
along with it anyway so
what we're going to do uh in this study
in this message is we're going to
understand the context so that you can
step back and see the big picture and
really get this okay that's what we're
after we're after understanding so no
matter who you are no matter what
Christian background you are from
Context is extremely important right we
don't want to contradict the Bible or
worse yet seem like Hypocrites by
telling the world thou shall not kill
it's a commandment you need to stop
abortion but at the same time we're
turning around and saying the law of God
has been nailed to the cross we don't
need to keep it anymore because Jesus
came that doesn't quite add up
okay so are you all ready put a one in
the chat if you're ready you'll alright
Pastor let's let's get the context let's
try to understand all right so let's do
that we're gonna go to Genesis chapter
one we're gonna go back to the beginning
we're gonna go to Genesis one and we're
gonna begin to paint a picture that is
hopefully by the grace of God gonna make
this very simple and hopefully
Unforgettable you will never be confused
about this again no matter what text you
read in the Bible that seems to be
saying one thing you'll be like oh
I get that now oh I get this now all
right watch so Genesis chapter one
and verse 27 heavenly father again we
pray that you give us understanding help
me to make this simple Lord help me to
make this plane in Jesus name amen
so when we go to Genesis chapter 1
beginning with verse 27 the Bible says
here so God created man in his own image
in the image of God created he him male
and female created he them
and God blessed them and God said unto
them be fruitful and multiply and
replenish the Earth and subdue it
replenish the Earth and subdue it so
let's pause right here for a second in
the beginning we know that God created
Mankind and he gave them a commission to
what be fruitful and multiply right so
man is supposed to cover the Earth with
with other men right with human beings
with Offspring be fruitful and multiply
we also know that God tells Adam and Eve
or Adam in the garden
Genesis 2 16 the Bible says and the Lord
God commanded the man saying of every
tree of the garden thou May is free to
eat but are the tree of the knowledge of
Good and Evil thou shall not eat of it
for in the day that thou eat is thereof
Thou shalt surely die so we know that
God commands man listen don't eat from
that tree of knowledge of Good and Evil
because if you do so you are going to
die you're going to die well we know
that in the very next chapter of the
Bible in Genesis chapter 3
the Bible says speaks about this serpent
that deceives Adam and Eve it's the
devil right in Genesis 3 1 the Bible
says now the serpent was more subtle
than any beast of the field which the
Lord God had made and he said unto the
woman yea has God said You shall not eat
of every tree of the garden and the
woman said unto the serpent we may eat
of the fruit of the Trees of the garden
but of the fruit of the tree which is in
the midst of the garden God has said You
shall not eat of it neither shall you
touch it lest you die
and the serpent said unto the woman you
shall not surely die for God does know
that in the day you eat thereof then
your eyes shall be open and ye shall be
as God's knowing good and evil and when
the woman saw that the tree was good for
food and that it was pleasant to the
eyes on the tree to be desired to make
one wise she took of the fruit thereof
and did eat and gave also to gave also
unto her husband with her and he did eat
and we know that this is how sin entered
right this is how sin entered okay
so
When sin enters When sin enters uh Adam
and Eve are now under a new
power
at that moment who is now ruling mankind
just put it in attack for me please who
is now ruling mankind the moment that
Eve as well as Adam eats from the tree
whose are they who do Adam and Eve now
rightfully belong to
very good very good they are now Satan's
they belong to him now let me ask you a
question
as they left as it were
as they begin to be fruitful and
multiply who do all that Offspring now
belong to
who do all The Offspring not belong to
right all that Offspring that's going to
be born they would belong to Satan
okay so just follow this if God had not
intervened then all The Offspring of
Adam and Eve would belong to Satan now
here's what we found is very interesting
go with me back to the screen and I want
you to notice Romans 5 verse 12. the
Bible says wherefore
as by one man
sin entered into the world and death by
sin and so death passed upon all men
for that all have sinned all right come
back come back
so
we know that when Adam and Eve sinned
they had given themselves over to the
devil and then giving themselves over to
the devil their offspring were also
given over to the devil because through
their sin all humankind was guilty
because all humankind were in their
loins
so did that make sense put a one in the
chat if that makes sense if you're
following me so far
all right so now if
if we're keeping track right Adam and
Eve the only two human beings on the
planet now belong to Satan
and
how many people does God have on the
planet as his own
zero
zero none Adam and Eve have now given
themselves over to death they've given
themselves over to Satan for him to rule
them
now
it is in that context that I want you to
check out Genesis 3 15.
Genesis 3 15 notice what it says on the
screen Genesis 3 15.
so God after giving Adam his punishment
and Eve her punishment he then turns to
the serpent and he begins to speak his
punishment and I want you to notice what
Genesis 3 15 says
Genesis 3 15 reads God speaking and I
will put enmity between thee and the
woman and between now watch this guys
thy seed and her seed it shall bruise
thy head and thou shalt bruise his heel
all right let's come back here so notice
this
God says I'm going to put enmity between
your seed and the woman's seed now what
does that indicate what does that
indicate
who would be the devil's seed
and I want y'all to think with me okay
who would that represent I want to see
if y'all put it in chat just want to see
if you can get who would that represent
who would the devil's seed or the
devil's Offspring as it were represent
you are for the devil who would that be
very good Rick it would be everybody it
would be mankind
it would be unbelievers very good
Carolina it would be unbelievers Sergio
says Cain very good Rob says us hmm
wow us
let me ask you which one of us were born
followers of Christ
none of us
none of us so watch what God is saying
here God is literally saying to Satan
look you may have just taken over all of
humanity but when God says I will put
enmity between the woman's seed and your
seed he has just spoken into existence
the fact that he is about to redeem a
people out of Satan's camp
put a one in the chat if that if if you
just caught that
you just got Adam and Eve okay and and
and in them is the whole Human family
but I'm letting you know that there's
gonna be enmity between your seed and
her seed God has just spoken a gospel
promise there I'm about to redeem
Humanity
and that Redemption is going to be
evident in her seed and and particularly
in one individual who is that seed that
that he's ultimately talking about he's
talking about Jesus Christ
are y'all with me so far
I know you like Pastor we're supposed to
be talking about the law trust me we're
gonna get there but I need you to
understand Genesis 3 15 first
okay no no
what is enmity
so so the the the the text said I will
put enmity between your seed and her
seed so enmity beloved is something that
is placed in between two individuals or
two groups to keep them separate
Rob very good enmity is division you're
either on this side or that side so God
says I'm going to put division between
my seed my people right
through the woman and through your
people please put a one in the chat and
you understand that
I'm gonna put division between my people
those who choose to follow me and those
who choose to follow you now I got a
question for you so think of it think of
it like division
enmity is division you might think of it
of something as something like a
partition it's opposition it's to be
against
right that's what enmity is I'm gonna
put something between my people and your
people and it's going to serve as a
buffer now watch this a lot of you are
saying ah Mutual hatred but let me ask
you a question is this enmity is it a
good thing or a bad thing
we're going to take a vote right now put
put
just go ahead and put the word bad or
good
let's see what you put in the chat is it
a bad thing or a good thing
all right so I see some saying good I
see some saying bad well let me just
tell you
that if God put it there
God said I will put enmity then it's a
good thing
now watch this guys God is putting
enmity now now now what he's doing is he
giving is he giving Satan seed enmity is
God putting a a a desire to stay apart
is he putting that in bad people in
people who are like I'm uh you know I am
Satan seed is that what he's doing no no
no no no no beloved God never puts
enmity against righteousness God is not
the author of making bad people hate
good people or bad people not want
anything to do with good people that's
not what God does because God's trying
to save how many he's trying to save
everybody
so the enmity he's putting there is in
his own people I'm going to create a
division that's going to separate my
people who I'm gathering by the way who
I'm redeeming from your Camp amen
amen I'm gonna put a a barrier of
protection I'm gonna put a a a a a a a
partition I'm gonna put a dividing wall
between my people and your people and
this is going to keep my people safe for
a reason for a purpose
so so number one the Bible says that he
was going to put enmity in other words a
buffer between his people and Satan's
people by the way I want you to know
this on the screen no note the text
he's going to put enmity note that first
thing James 4 4 you adulterers and
adulteresses no you're not that
friendship of the world is enmity with
God whosoever therefore shall be a
friend of the world is the enemy of God
so see that enmity means that you're for
for something and against something
you're on one side or the other there's
a dividing wall between you and that
other thing
all right all right so let's keep moving
someone said
who's the devil's seat is that us let me
let me get your answer from this Romans
3 23 all have sinned and come short of
the glory of God so let me ask you a
question who was the devil's seed
who was the devil's seed
everybody
but God said I'm gonna separate a people
out of that seed now please just follow
along don't even worry about the law
right now because when we get to it
you're going to be like ah you Pastor
you don't have to say anymore I get it
now so just follow along follow along
so so enmity God says I'm gonna put
enmity I'm gonna draw out a people right
out of your Offspring and they're gonna
be my people and I'm gonna separate them
I'm gonna put a dividing wall between my
people and your people
those who follow me and serve me versus
those who follow you and serve you now I
want you to know this again Isaiah 59
verse 1 behold the Lord's hand is not
shortened that he cannot save neither is
this here heavy baby can I hear but your
iniquities have separated between you
and your God and your sins have hit his
face from you that he will not hear your
hands are defiled with blood
and your fingers with iniquity your lips
have spoken lies your tongue has mudded
perverseness none calleth for truth nor
any plea for truth they trust in vanity
and speak lies they conceive mischief
and bring forth iniquity let me rephrase
it this way all
all
who
are against God
because of their sins are the devil's
offspring remember how Jesus said in the
book of uh in the in the in the gospels
when you talk to the Pharisees he said
you are of your father the devil and his
works you do you have your father the
devil so that gives you an idea the
devil's seed would be all the wicked God
the woman's seed will be those who come
out of that group to serve God okay
so we see that God gives a a a a a in
fact no no let me let me go back here
let me go back here
um no we can do that Genesis 3 21 on to
Adam also and to his wife did the Lord
God give coats of skin and cold them
this is his act of redemption this is
his act of redemption right when he when
he gives them these coats of skins how
do they get these coats of skins an
animal had to die
So Adam and Eve are the first per people
redeemed under the gospel umbrella
did you catch that
Adam and Eve are the first people
redeemed under the gospel umbrella and
how do we know that because when God
clothed them
he had an animal had to die in order to
cover them to cover their nakedness
are y'all with me so far
okay not only does the prophecy say that
he would put a a enmity between his
people and God's people but it goes on
to say that that this seed would bruise
the head of the serpent
okay so number one I will put enmity
number two I'm gonna bruise that my son
Christ is going to defeat or bruise the
head of the serpent right so y'all get
that and all of you are very familiar
with this but I'm about to show you
something now
you're about to see something now
because there's a third part of this
prophecy you see
in
defeating watch this in defeating the
enemy that is in defeating Christ
he would then remove the enmity okay
now I know that y'all are not getting
this you may not get this right now
remove the enmity what he put it there
watch this he put the enmity there
because of what Satan did now he says uh
so I'm gonna put enmity my son is gonna
bruise your head that means I'm gonna
defeat you and then we're gonna see that
as a result of saying being defeat Satan
being defeated he will in essence remove
the enmity
foreign
I know what you're thinking right now
why would God remove the enmity
why would he get rid of the image so
hold on we're about to lay this down
okay
so we know that this is Genesis right we
see here we're looking for three things
number one he's gonna put enmity number
two he's going to destroy the Devil and
then number three he's going to remove
the enmity now I haven't proven to you
yet about removing the enmity all I've
shown you from scripture is that he put
enmity and that he would bruise the head
of the serpent okay
so we know that in Leviticus chapter 20
uh chapter 22 chapter 20 verse 22 that
um God has called Israel out of Egypt
he has separated a people for himself
out of out of the world it's a peculiar
people and we read in Leviticus 20 verse
22 you shall therefore keep all my
statues and all my judgments and shall
do them that the land whether I bring
you to dwell therein spew not out and
you shall not walk in the manner of the
Nations which I cast out before you for
they committed all these things and
therefore I abort them watch this but
I've said unto you you shall inherit the
land and I will give it unto you to
possess it a land that flows with milk
and honey I'm the Lord your God which
have done what
separated you from other people
separated you from other people let me
just throw another one in here very
quick First Kings 8 53 for thou did
separate them from among all the people
of the earth to be thine inheritance as
thou stake is by the hand of Moses thy
servant when thou brought our fathers
out of Egypt so let's just recap here
what do we see God doing here is God has
God separated for himself a people is
there The Offspring of the woman is
there the seed of the woman and also the
seed of the world yes or no put a one in
the chat if you're following so far okay
I get it God separated His People Israel
from the rest of the world put a one in
the chat if you get that thus far
I'm following you Pastor I I I I got
this yes
he separated his people right and and
and now you've got two distinct lines
you had them before Israel right you had
the sons of God in Genesis 6 and the
daughters of men in Genesis 6 just when
the flood was happening so we've always
seen that line Cain and Abel yeah
right you can just just go down the line
and Trace the lineage of of those who
serve God and those who shall say so the
seed of the woman and the seed of the
devil Cain would have been the seed of
the devil yes
okay
so now God's got a whole group of people
it's a nation Israel and he separates
them we see that in the text now I want
you to notice what he does next
in Exodus 34 verse 28 watch this watch
this all right now now y'all can get
ready now y'all can get ready and that's
what's 34 28
speaking of Moses he was there with the
Lord 40 days and 40 nights he didn't
either eat bread nor drink water and he
wrote upon the tables the words of the
Covenant the Tana what everyone the Ten
Commandments
The Ten Commandments okay
so God here is now giving the children
of Israel a law
what is that law
the law
is called the ten command not the 12
Commandments not the 15 Commandments not
the 600 Commandments but the Ten
Commandments and they're written on
Stone now what do I want you to
understand about these Commandments well
first of all the most important thing I
need you to understand is this
these Ten Commandments Thou shalt not
kill right thou shall not commit
adultery thou shall not lie Thou shalt
not steal honor thy father and thy
mother Thou shalt have no other gods
before me thou shall not take the name
of the Lord in vain remember this
happened keep it holy these Commandments
listen carefully
describe
sin
they are the description of sin put a
one in the chat if that makes sense to
you the Ten Commandments are the
description of sin if you kill it is sin
if you lie it is sin if you commit
adultery it is sin if you if you are
covet it is sin The Ten Commandments
describe what sin is this is why the
Bible says in First John 3 4 whosoever
committed sin transgresses also the law
for sin is a transgression of the law
and this is why Romans 3 verse 20 says
therefore by the Deeds of the law shall
no flesh be justified in the sight for
by the law is the knowledge of sin so in
other words
what Paul is saying here is that the
only purpose that the law serves that
when he's talking specifically about the
Ten Commandments now is to tell you what
sin is
remember Paul said I had not known uh uh
um what is it I've not known uh lust
except the loss of thou shall not covet
he's saying listen the law tells me what
sin is
the law is the description of sin
so so the children of Israel were
commanded to to
not sin to keep the Commandments of God
don't lie don't steal Etc okay y'all
good with that so far now I'm going to
introduce you to something else and I
want you to watch this
in the video what happened to someone
sinned what happened if someone sinned
that's the question right how did God
deal with sin so the Commandments only
reveal okay you're in the guilty
category right you sinned now how does
how did God deal with sin in the Old
Testament
so I want you to watch again I want you
to notice what's on the screen
look for verse one Leviticus 4 verse 1
I'm sorry and the Lord spake unto Moses
saying Speak unto the children of Israel
saying if a soul shall sin through
ignorance against any of The
Commandments of the Lord concerning
things which ought not to be done and
shall do against any of them
if the priests and so they give they go
through and save as a priest if it's a
ruler
Etc right and this is just an example if
the priesthood is Anointed to do sin
according to the sin of the people then
let him bring forth his sin which he has
sinned a young Bullock without blemish
unto the Lord for a sin offering
so let me ask you a question
what happened if a person sinned in the
Old Testament
what would they have to do
they would have to perform
a ceremony
and that ceremony was a sacrifice
right it's a ceremony it's kind of it's
a ritual that you go through in order to
be forgiven for what breaking the law
what law so watch this there was a law
so there's the law that describes sin
okay there's a law that describes sin
and then there's something else that was
done when one broke that law and look
again at what the Bible says Hebrews 9
22 almost all things are by the law
Purge with blood and without shedding of
blood is no remission so let me ask you
a question
what law is Paul talking about here and
almost all things are by the law purged
with blood what law is he talking about
when you read The Ten Commandments do
you do you see anything about the need
to bring blood or the need to shed blood
in order to forgive sins
no there's nothing in the Ten
Commandments that talks about sacrifice
right or how you're forgiven for your
sins it's just the description of sin
but there was another law given that was
what we will call the prescription for
sin
this is the ceremonial law
the ceremony like what is the ceremony
that is necessary to carry out if one
has sinned ah if you sin if you break
the law then the response is the remedy
is the cure is
the ceremonial law
you have to sacrifice an animal
put a one in the chat if that's clear
for you right now
the the ceremonial law the the moral law
was the description or is the
description of sin the ceremonial law
was the prescription for sin
oh I sinned I want to be forgiven okay
well this is what you need to do
are y'all good so far
okay excellent very good very good so
let's keep moving so
here's a question now
um that's a good thing God has provided
for his people there's a there's a issue
and that is sin but God has provided for
his people the remedy for sin now let me
ask you a question what about the
devil's seed
what about the devil's seed
let's say that they did something wrong
could they walk up into the camp of
Israel and be like man
only way to get forgiveness is to just
like you know go offer up an animal
could they do that yes or no
so y'all are already jumping ahead of me
y'all are already seeing this
could they do that
no they could not do that so let me try
to phrase it this way
there was something blocking them
from Gaining access to the cure for sin
put a fire Emoji in the chat if you just
got that
put put a one whatever you need to put
in the chat just put that there for me
so I know you got that there was
something there was a a wall a a series
of of things that that separated them
from having access to the Cure so
remember God says I'm going to put
enmity so that I'm gonna separate my
people from the world the world is not
going to be able to just to just you
know find they're they're going to be
separate from what my people have access
to
there's there's your seed and there's my
seed my people
my people
when they sin they're gonna have a cure
for that sin
but your people when they sin they have
no cure
is all hope lost
for the devil's seed watch watch follow
this guys follow this watch this
is there a way that they could get
access that this the the these you know
what they what the Jews would call
Gentiles right or or or the Heathen
right or the devil's seed was there a
way that they could have access to gain
access to the cure for sin which in the
Old Testament was sacrifice the shedding
of blood
I want you to notice what Exodus 12 43
says this is the Passover the Lord's
speaking about here the Bible says here
this and the Lord said unto Moses Moses
and Aaron this is the ordinance of the
Passover there shall No Stranger eat
thereof now I need you to get this right
the Passover is the very first Festival
of the Jewish year
No Stranger was allowed to eat the
Passover so let me ask you a question
let me ask you a question let's just
come back here real quick
let's say that you were a stranger let's
say that you were a stranger right
you're uh you know you're an Egyptian
and you're like man I just feel this
weight of guilt on me but
and I believe that the god of Israel can
can save me from that weight of guilt
but wait a minute
I can't eat of the Passover
I can't get access to the ceremonial
system
that cures my guilt this is the Old
Testament I can't get rid of this I
can't get access there's it's like I
would like to but there is this wall and
the wall says if you're not an Israelite
you can't enter in put a one in the chat
if you get that there is this this
separation it almost feels like enmity
like man does God have something against
me
why can't I have access
all right let's keep moving let's let's
go back to the text Exodus 12 44 but
every man's servant that is brought for
money when thou has circumcised them
then shall he wait what when you have
what hold on hold on
a foreigner and a hired servant shall
not eat thereof
in one house shall it be eaten Thou
shalt not carry forth out of the flesh
abroad out of the house neither shall
you break a bone thereof watch this
verse 47 and all the congregation of
Israel shall keep it now verse 48 and
when a stranger sojourns with thee and
will keep the Passover to the Lord let
all his males be circumcised and then
let them come near and keep it and he
shall be as one that is born in the land
for no uncircumcised person shall eat
thereof all right y'all
put a one in the chat
what was the one thing that those who
were afar off meaning the devil seed
right the devil seed they have been
separated by enmity right God has put
enmity something that is against a
stranger not against his people that is
against a stranger huh man look at
Israel they're getting saved over there
they got salvation over there I want to
get in but I can't there's this wall
there's this wall of laws that per that
that exclude me from getting access to
the Cure
but you know God is merciful right
he says listen
if if you who are on the devil's seed
truly wants salvation then
the answer is
in order to get access to the Cure right
the sacrifices that bring forgiveness in
the Old Testament in order to get access
you must be what everyone come on put it
in the chat y'all you must be what
circumcised and then you can come near
remember that phrase y'all then you can
come near so in order for them to come
because they were far
enmity
there's a distance there's a separation
this thing is against you but if you
want to come near
man you're going to have to go through
something quite painful
you're going to have to be circumcised
as an adult whoo
not only you but your whole family of
men that's what the text says let him
and all the males in his family be
circumcised Whoa man that was difficult
watch this let's keep moving let's keep
moving I want you to see this so so so
know here then in Ephesians chapter 2
verse 11 wherefore remember that you
being time past Gentiles In the Flesh
who are called
uncircumcision by that which is called
the circumcision in the flesh made by
hands that without that at that time you
are without Christ being aliens from the
Commonwealth of Israel and strangers
from the Covenant of Promise having no
hope and without God do you see this
let me read that again
wherefore
remember
oh okay
hold on a second y'all
give me one second
I need to do something here so let me
just
let me just do this
and I'm going to share some text with
you that um
that actually
didn't have up here let's let's do this
let's do this
ah
okay
so I want you to watch this guys I want
you to watch this
so so
here's a question let me go back to the
slide here's a question
how how was this against Satan's seed
right that's the question how was this
this law of circumcision against the
seed of Satan well number one you could
not get access to the Cure unless you
were circumcised so so let me let me go
back to this you understand that The
Cure and the prescription for sin and
the description for sin are two
different things
one law describes sin the other law
points you to the cure for sin and
that's under the Old Testament
are you are you catching what I'm saying
okay so so the question again is how was
this against or in opposition almost how
is this difficult for the for the
Gentile for the person that was not an
Israelite well number one notice notice
on screen number one
you could not get access to the Cure
unless you were circumcised
number two
the Gentiles would have to Journey to
the temple to get access
in other words if you were far away from
from the temple like you lived in a in a
totally different Nation
the only way for you to get salvation
you couldn't just be in your house and
be like well uh let me off up a lamb no
no no no you had to go to the temple
watch watch Leviticus 4 4 he shall bring
the Bullock onto the door of the
Tabernacle before the Lord and shall lay
his hand upon a Bullock and kill the
bullet before the before the Lord so in
other words Israel wasn't really worried
about that because the temple was right
in their midst
but if you're a gentile you gotta go to
the temple
you may have to travel
hundreds and hundreds of miles
wait wait there's more number three Not
only was it to be done in the temple it
was to be done in Jerusalem and no other
place notice Deuteronomy 12 10. but when
you go over the Jordan and dwell on the
land which the Lord your God given you
to inherit and when he giveth you the
rest from all your enemies round about
so that you dwell in the land safely
then shall there be a place which the
Lord your God shall choose to cause his
name to dwell there thither shall ye
bring all that I command you watch this
you guys your burnt offerings and your
sacrifices your tithes and your heed
offerings of your hand and all your
choice vows which you shall make unto
the Lord watch this and you shall
rejoice before the Lord your God you and
your sons your daughters your man's
servants your main servants and the Levi
that is within your gates for as much as
he has no part of the inheritance with
you take heed to yourself that you offer
not by Burnt offering in every place
that you see but in a place which the
Lord shout choose in one of those tribes
therefore Thou shalt offer
thy birth offering
and there thus there shalt thou do what
I command thee so in other words beloved
you couldn't be in Texas
give me a one in the chat if you
understand what I just say you couldn't
be in you know in in in Jamaica or
France or some other place and just be
like ah you know what I mean forgiveness
right now so let me just like throw up
an altar in my house no no no no no you
had to go
think about those who lived afar off
the only way that they could get there
is that they had to travel great
distances from one nation to another man
that sounds pretty difficult y'all
how about this how about this not only
did they have to travel watch this I
need you to see this okay
let's just go back to the description
for sin was there circumcision required
to keep the law thou shall not kill was
circumcision required
to keep that commandment
was circumcision required for a person
to
keep the Commandment do not bear false
witness I want you to watch this no
circumcision was required
to do any one of these Commandments
number two no Temple was required to
keep any of these Commandments
no Temple No sacrifice in order not to
steal you don't have to give a sacrifice
first and go to the temple no no no no
it's just do not steal
none of these Commandments
require you to go to Jerusalem to keep
them
not on the Lord your God you can keep
that anywhere no idolatry you can keep
that anywhere do not take the name of
the Lord today you can keep that
anywhere remember the sound to keep
holding you can keep that anywhere I'm
your mother and father do not commit
adultery no murder no sin you can keep
those anywhere no sacrifice no Temple no
circumcision was required to keep the
description of the law or what we call
the description of sin no no
circumcision Temple sacrifice Jerusalem
visit required nothing
but if you are trying to get the Cure
The Cure was only local so watch this
the description of sin was Universal
anywhere in the world where someone
kills it is sin anywhere in the world
where someone lies it is sin anywhere in
the world where someone works with
Graven name is it is sin but in those
days the prescription for sin was only
local meaning it was only in Israel
now
watch this guys
so we've just clearly identified that
Jesus that God himself put enmity
between his seed and the seed of the
devil there was a separation a
distinction and they could not get
access to forgiveness of sins unless
they were to go through that most
discouraging wall of circumcision
if you are circumcised then you could
keep the Passover then you could keep
the first fruits then you could keep all
these feasts which all were connected
with sacrifices in other words were all
designed to be a part of the process of
cleansing from sin
now that's part one of the prophecy I
will put enmity between thee and the
woman now the second part of the
prophecy is I will my scene will bruise
the head of the serpent and we know this
happened that Calvary Matthew 27 33 and
when they were coming to a place called
Golgotha that is to say a place of a
skull please note here I love this Jesus
died on a skull-shaped hill remember the
prophecy says that Jesus would bruise
the head of the serpent the hill is
called Calvary which in the Greek is
Cranium
it's also called Golgotha which is
literally called the place of a skull
when Jesus died he was breaking the the
head the skull as it were of of Satan
now now watch this guys watch what
happens when Jesus
dies and in essence crushes the skull of
the serpent watch what the text says
Matthew 27 33.
and when they were coming to a place
called Golgotha that is to say the place
of a skull there it is just so you can
see it just you can have reference now
watch this Jesus when he cried again
with a loud voice and yielded up The
Ghost and behold the veil of the temple
was rent in Twain from top to bottom and
the Earth did Quake now let me ask you a
question y'all let me ask you a question
when the veil of the temple is rent in
two
what does that signify
what did that signify
what was shut down
come on y'all what was shut down
the place
where people went
to get cured of sin has been shut down
God why would you do that
what are people going to do now when
they sin
what will people do now if they lie or
steal or commit adultery those things
still exist y'all the description for
sin is the very same as it was in the
Old Testament
the description Remains the Same but
evidently God is saying I'm shutting
down the house where I used to you know
make available a cure because a new cure
is coming
mm-hmm
and if a new cure is coming then we have
no need for the system which provided an
old cure
put a one in the chat no put a seven in
the chat y'all if y'all are catching
this right now when the temple is sucked
down what God is demonstrating here is
that the prescription is about to become
Universal
through the blood of Christ and beloved
watch this the prescription becoming
Universal does nothing to change the
description of sin the description of
sin is still the same thing killing in
the New Testament is the same as killing
in the old lying today is the same as
lying in the garden
stealing today is the same as stealing
back then the description of sin Remains
the Same but what Jesus has come to do
away with is an
ineffective cure
The Cure was only symbolic of something
that was to come in the future and that
thing that was to come in the future was
the very blood of Jesus yes the vaccine
was upgraded to one that really works
are you all catching this
Not only was the temple no longer
significant the temple would be
destroyed beloved in 70 A.D But Not only
was the temple destroyed watch this look
at the text Luke 21 24 and they shall
fall by the edge of the sword and Sabi
LED away captive into all nations and
Jerusalem
shall be trodden Down Under the Gentiles
until the times of the Gentiles should
be fulfilled in other words not only
Not only was the temple destroyed but
the City was destroyed meaning listen
guys meaning
watch this
the
Temple where the prescription was found
and the City where you could where the
the spirit the prescription was found
both are now destroyed
it's almost as if in Christ's death the
enmity when he bruises the head of Satan
he now says okay I'm about to remove
I'm about to remove the separating wall
and now
I'm about to remove the enmity watch
this guys in Galatians 5 6 15
for in Christ Jesus neither circumcision
availeth anything nor uncircumcision but
a new creature circumcision is no longer
required to get access to the remedy do
you understand that Jesus Christ in
dying became our circumcision
so now for the Gentile who is now trying
to look for salvation guess what's been
removed he no longer has to go through
the painful process of circumcision all
he needs is a circumcision of the heart
all right how else was the enmity
removed circumcision no longer needed
watch this watch this guys a journey to
the temple under the New Covenant a
journey to the temple is no longer
needed to get access to the Cure number
two a journey to Jerusalem is no longer
required to get access to the Cure and
number three actually number four number
one is the circumcision number two is
the journeys of December number three is
the journey to Jerusalem and number four
the cure itself has been updated and is
now universally available
thank you
how are y'all doing
are y'all getting the context
so now when we go to the New Testament
and we start reading right we start
reading these verses that when we read
them out of context we're just like well
it must mean the law of God's done away
with no no no no now I understand watch
this beloved in this new system there's
a new way to get forgiveness it's no
longer circumcision it's no longer going
to the temple it's no longer going to
Jerusalem now in Christ
when I sin
when I lie when I steal when I come in
adultery in Christ I have a new means of
forgiveness Christ hasn't done away with
the description for sin he has done away
with the prescription for sin
did y'all catch that watch this watch
this we're about to we got a few more
texts parts of chapters and then we're
going to be done so just follow this
having therefore Brethren boldness to
enter into the holiest by the blood of
Jesus by a New and Living Way what does
that mean no longer do I need to be
circumcised no longer do I need to
travel to a temple no longer do I need
to go to Jerusalem if I want to be cured
from my line and stealing no no no
there's a new way now and that new way
is through his flesh
his flesh has taken the place of that
enmity
he is concentrated for us a new way
through the veil that is to say through
his flesh that means his death and
having the high priest over the house of
God let us draw near oh man ah yes yes
yes let us draw near watch this guys you
could not draw near before unless you
were circumcised in heart I mean in
flesh then you could draw near remember
the text we just read it remember let's
go back to it
let's go back let's go back nope it's
not there we're just going to keep
moving forward so in in other words they
had to draw in order for them to draw
near they have to be circumcised not
anymore not anymore that's been done
away with
let us draw near with a true heart and
full Assurance of Faith having our
hearts sprinkled from the evil
conscience and our bodies washed with
pure water how about this Ephesians 2
for he is our peace who has made both
one and has broken down the middle wall
of partition between us what was that
middle wall of partition you got to be
circumcised if you want to join us
you got to come to Jerusalem if you want
to join us
you got to come to the temple all right
you trying to say you're not the devil's
seat anymore you want to be down with us
you got to be circumcised you got to
come to Jerusalem you got to come to the
temple that's what and you got to
sacrifice if you want to be down with us
Jesus says no longer
I've gotten rid of that middle wall
watch this having a balance in his flesh
the enmity
did you see that
having abolished in his flesh the what
enmity the enmity back there in Genesis
3 15. I'm getting rid of it now because
I bruised the devil's head and now I'm
opening the way for everyone so I'm
getting rid of the law of Commandments
contained in ordinances this is um it's
the prescription of sin that he's
getting rid of
so that he can make in himself of Twain
one new man and soul making peace that
he might reconcile both unto God and one
body of the Cross having slain the
enmity thereby and came and preached
peace to you which were what are far off
the devil's seed the devil's Offspring
and to them that were nigh in Christ's
death he has gotten rid of the enmity
that he himself put there and said now
you want to access salvation it's all
open why because I just defeated the
devil
I just defeated the devil
I'm opening up the way to Salvation to
everyone so it doesn't matter if you're
in China it doesn't matter if you're in
Spain it doesn't matter if you're if
you're an African it doesn't matter if
you're in America it doesn't matter
where you are the blood of Christ is is
is you can get it anywhere
come on guys we're almost done almost
there notice Ephesians 2 4 by grace for
by grace are you saved through faith and
not of yourselves it is the gift of God
not of words lest any man should boast
what he's saying here in the very same
chapter is this listen you are not saved
anymore by that circumcision of the Old
Testament you're no longer saved by
going to the temple and going to
Jerusalem no no no no you are saved by
grace through faith that means by the
simple access of Christ wherever you are
when you sin
when you realize I'm I'm in sin
when you realize that the description of
sin has condemned you yes you're guilty
of sin yes you're guilty of lying yes
you're guilty of murdering yes you're
guilty of worship engraving images yes
you're guilty of putting other gods
before you before God when you realize
that whoa this this is pointing to me
now the Cure is in the blood of Jesus
the blood of Jesus forgives you of your
sin it does not wipe out what sin is let
me say it again
the blood of Jesus does not nullify the
Commandment that says thou shall not
kill that doesn't make any sense why
would Jesus come and get rid of the
description of the law
he came to offer a new prescription to
forgive you of your sin which sin is
defined as the breaking of The
Commandments God has not gotten rid of
the law Jesus has not gotten rid of the
law what he got rid of was the was the
process whereby one gains access to
forgiveness the ceremonial law has been
done away with everyone this is why
Hebrews 2 14 says this for as much then
as the children are partakers of Flesh
and Blood he also likewise himself took
part of the same watch this
that through death
he might destroy him that had the power
of death that is the devil and deliver
them
who through fear of death were all their
lifetimes subject to bondage in other
words I'm coming to deliver the devil's
seed
I'm gonna defeat the Devil and then
deliver those who were under his bondage
deliver those who were of his seed but
it's only they have to make the Free
Will choice to do it I'm not just going
to deliver them okay everybody save now
no no no no they have to choose to be
circumcised in the heart and then this
is why the Bible says now if you love me
keep my Commandments I delivered you
keep my Commandments he's not talking
about go sacrifice animals he's talking
about don't lie don't steal don't kill
don't commit adultery he's talking about
dogs I have no other gods before me the
Commandments of God have not changed my
my beloved Christian friend
so watch this
Genesis 3 15 number one he would put
enmity that's the Old Testament that's
the ceremonial law number two he would
bruise the head of the serpent he did
that at the cross to provide a new cure
and number three he now removes the
enmity he removes the ceremonial law
that that which divided you from Gentile
and he says now in me
in me there is neither Jew nor Gentile
circumcision nor uncircumcision in me it
is only Christ
do y'all get it
do y'all understand what was done away
with
and what still stands
Hebrews 10 1 for the law having a shadow
of good things to come and not the very
image of those things can never with
those sacrifices which they offered year
by year make the comers there unto
perfect watch this
for then would they not have ceased to
be offered because that the worshipers
once purged should have no more
conscience of sin but in those
sacrifices there is a remembrance again
made of sins every year for it is not
possible that the blood of bulls and
goats ceremonial law that's my emphasis
right there I put that in there
ceremonial law for it so it is not
possible that the blood of Boom of goats
the ceremonial law should take away sins
the moral law
wherefore he cometh into the world he's
safe sacrifice an offering would would
not thou it's not but a body has thou
prepared for me in burnt offering and
sacrifices for sin ceremonial law for
moral law thou has no pleasure then said
I lo I come in the volume of the book it
is written of me to do thy Willow God
above when he said sacrifice and
offering and burnt offerings for sin
thou it's not neither had pleasure
therein which are offered by the law
then said I lo I come to do thy will o
God he taketh away the first that's the
first cure that he may establish the
second that's the second cure wherefore
the Holy Ghost also is of witness to us
for after that he said before this is
the Covenant I will make with them after
those days say the Lord I will put my
laws into their hearts and in their
minds will I write them hmm
hmm
how y'all doing
I hope this is making sense to you I got
one listen Colossians 2 this is one of
the other go-to verses listen and watch
how we now
understands Watch what it says Watch
what it says Colossians 2 10 and you are
completing him which is the head and
principality of power in whom also you
are circumcised with the circumcision
made without hands and putting off the
body of the sins of the flesh by the
circumcision of Christ see that
buried with him in baptism wherein also
you are risen with him through the faith
of the operation of God who has raised
him from the dead watch this and you
being dead in your sins and the
uncircumcision of your flesh has he
quickened together with him having
forgiven all your trespasses watches
blotting out the handwriting of
ordinances that was against us
you got to be circumcised
you have to offer these sacrifices you
have to come to the temple you have to
come to Jerusalem but I live 100 miles
away doesn't matter
blotting out the handwriting of
ordinances that was against us which was
contrary to us circumcised at 20 are you
sure yes and all you and all the boys in
your house
and took that out of the way nailing not
to the cross
that's what he got rid of guys so Romans
2 25 for circumcision verily profited if
you keep the law but if you be a breaker
of the law then circumcision is your
circumcision is made uncircumcision
therefore if the uncircumcision keep the
righteousness of the law shall not his
uncircumcision be counted for
circumcision
I hope y'all are catching this I hope
this is making sense John 14 15 Jesus
said if you love me keep my Commandments
Romans 13 8 oh no man anything but to
love one another for he that loveth
another has fulfilled the law Beloved
the law still stands Romans 39 for this
thou shall not commit adultery thou
shall not kill thou shall not steal thou
shall not bear false witness thou shall
not covet and if there be any other
commandment it is briefly comprehended
in this saying namely Thou shalt love
thy neighbor as thyself love worketh no
ill to his neighbor therefore love is
the fulfilling of the law beloved Jesus
said it himself in Matthew 22 the two
great Commandments are to love God and
to love your neighbor as yourself and
these are not two new Commandments they
come from the Old Testament
here's my final slide guys
my final slide
in Daniel 2 you got to understand this
in Daniel 2
Nebuchadnezzar is given a dream
zeonda me too
me too all of this goal if you
understand Genesis 3 15
you have the foundation to understand
what was the enmity that was put there
and was removed and it makes clear
crystal clear what law still stands and
what law was done away with listen
Nebuchadnezzar's dream he sees these
nations Rising represented by this image
of a man and then a stone that is cut
out of a mountain without hands destroys
the image on its feet why is that
significant it's it's significant for
one simple Reason Not only does this
Stone represent Christ I want you to
understand that but there is only one
other place in the scripture where Stone
cut out of a mountain without hands
occurred
and that is the law of God that's the
Ten Commandments
the world is on a moral decline
and it is because the world has turned
its back on the Ten Commandments but the
world has turned its back on the Ten
Commandments because they're simply
following the example of the church who
is preaching from pulpits every weekend
that the law of God that we're no longer
under great under the law were under
grace the law has been done away with
and the and the confusing part about
this is that they will turn around and
speak to the heathens saying You must
keep the Commandments of God
thou shall not kill the law of God
hasn't changed these are not 10
suggestions these are Ten Commandments
you took the law out of public schools
and public places beloved listen to me
the law of God was never meant to be in
public places the law of God was meant
to be written in the heart on these
tables right here my appeal to you
you're watching this you've heard this
for the first time you didn't understand
ah man I should be keeping the law and
listen I'm telling you you will get
slack you will get the Bible says the
devil goes to make war with those who
keep the Commandments of God
if you decide today I got to keep the
Commandments I don't care what my
preacher says I don't care what it the
law of God still stands and I understand
it now the devil is going to come at you
best believe that understand that but
beloved God has you
God's going to protect you
God is going to keep you
and so I'm appealing to you as you as
you listen to this go back and search
the scriptures for yourself and see if
what I said is so search the scriptures
and beloved
when the spirit of God shows you truth
I I implore you to follow it
I implore you to follow it
so please put a one in the chat if this
made sense to you just just put a one in
the chat if this made sense to you I'm
gonna this every
end of the month at the end of the month
I'm gonna be preaching another message
that is going to connect with what you
heard today it's going to be all
doctrinal so I'm doing this once a month
by the grace of God if you're looking
for truth if you've been confused about
certain things and you're looking for
truth I I would encourage you to tune in
because you're not going to want to miss
these okay
I want you to pray with me Heavenly
Father
today there are those who are struggling
with what they've heard because they
have heard truth
and now they're wondering what to do
with it Lord I pray that your spirit
would guide them would strengthen them
would encourage them would give them
holy boldness
Lord we give them understanding the
understanding that you've given them
today Lord give them the courage to walk
out to step out on that understanding
and to do as you have said if you love
me keep my Commandments tell them to
understand that the law of God that was
written with your own finger is not done
away with that is the description of sin
what Jesus Christ came to abolish was
the old cure and replace it with
something that is universally available
please Lord It's that simple it's that
simple
so Lord help us to grasp this truth
because if we can grasp this truth then
the other truths that ought to follow
will be easy to understand and
everything will begin to make sense and
so that I'm praying for those who are
watching this now and those who will
watch this by faith in the future
please let your spirit attend them as
they listen
and may conviction take over their
hearts as my prayer in Jesus name amen
and amen
I want to thank you guys for tuning in
to this if you're watching this for the
first time whether you're watching this
live now or you're watching it in the
future and you want to get more
information Pastor I need more
understanding on this law of God thing
I'm going to encourage you to email the
church okay specifically you can email
Patrice at Living Mana uh dot live and
she will get the email either to me or
to Rick our Bible worker and we will
follow up on it okay
so God bless you I want to encourage
those of you that are on who want to
stay on a state or after for the altar
live we'll put the all to live link up
in the in the chat uh there it is if you
want to get on for the after discussion
please feel free to join us there and uh
you guys be blessed uh and I will see
you next week
God bless
thank you for worshiping with us today
if this is your first time visiting with
us we invite you to check out our
website at livingmanna.live there you
will learn more about our mission to
reach the world with the Gospel of Jesus
we have exciting live programs
throughout the week covering topics like
physical health mental health prayer
learning how to prove God's existence
and much more if you would like to
support the ministry you can click on
the tithe and offering link on our
website we ask that you continue to pray
for the church as God continues to open
doors for our programming to reach the
world thank you again for your prayers
and your support
foreign